[{"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Do you have experience creating business proposals, property summary books, and new business presentations?", "answers": ["A Commercial Broker will work very hard to keep up to date on what is happening in their local market. This knowledge can then go into property summaries, business proposals, and client presentations, to showcase facts, stats, history, and other vital pieces of information that most business owners want and need before making a significant investment decision. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about your experience creating these types of materials. If you are newer to your career, you may not take the reins on a project like this, but perhaps you support senior brokers in your office as they build these materials. Whatever your experience level be sure to show the interviewer that you understand the importance of these business materials.", "\"I bring many years' experience in creating business proposals and property summary books. As a team leader in my current office, I also train other junior brokers on how to gather the information needed for these types of client materials. As far as business presentations, I build at least two new presentations in PowerPoint every week and am very comfortable doing so.\"", "\"As a junior broker, I do have experience building business presentations alongside more senior brokers. I have received some mentorship and training when it comes to building proposals and market summaries; however, I am not yet in the position to build these entirely on my own. I am learning, however, and becoming better every week.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Commercial Brokers spend a lot of time negotiating the best possible outcomes for their clients. How would you describe your negotiation skills?", "answers": ["Commercial real estate requires a lot of negotiating when it comes to contract inclusions and financial matters. The interviewer would like to see that you have the chops needed to make it in this fierce industry where every number and contract detail matters. \n\nSometimes, in real estate, parties are often stuck making concessions and demands on a single issue, such as price. How do you ensure that both parties get what they want?", "\"I would describe my negotiation skills as competitive yet friendly. I never underestimate the importance of starting a negotiation off right, with a friendly introductory phone call or a sentence or two that creates common ground. Research shows that you and your counterpart are more likely to reach an agreement if you spend a short amount of time getting to know each other.\"", "\"I am newer to my career and, although a confident negotiator, I believe in the importance of perfecting a variety of negotiation styles. At times, I take a collaborative approach where other times I take the approach of searching for smart tradeoffs, or other times, presenting multiple equivalent simultaneous offers. MESOs is a style that I learned through a Harvard online course that I recently completed. It's been beneficial when closing deals for my clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Company ABC keeps a close eye on Commercial Broker targets and wins. What type of goals did you set for yourself this year?", "answers": ["Some of the targets and goals that a Commercial Broker might be looking out for include number of clients, number of exclusive listings, amount of commission per transaction, new meetings booked, cold calls completed, number of referrals, and presentations made. \n\nOf course, these goals may differ depending on your seniority and the brokerages for which you have worked. Discuss with the interviewer the type of goals you have set for yourself, and if you have met or exceeded these goals.", "\"Goal setting has been a significant factor in my success as a Commercial Broker over the past eight years. I set goals every year and revisit them each quarter. So far this year, I have exceeded my goal of making 50 cold calls per week; averaging 62 at the moment. I also set the goal of 5 new meetings booked per week, a 10% cold call conversion. At this point, I have converted 14% of my cold calls.\"", "\"I appreciate that Company ABC is keen on numbers, targets, and goal setting. I am highly analytical by nature and have made a habit of reviewing my numbers every week, month, and quarter. Right now, as I build my business, the numbers that I keep the strongest eye on are new clients acquired, new meetings booked, and presentations made. I have landed sixteen new clients this year so far, and have many more good prospects on the go. The key for me is never taking my foot off the gas when it comes to lead generation and cold calling activities.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Company ABC is seeking a Commercial Broker with education in business, finance, economics, or other related coursework. Please walk me through your schooling.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like further detail on your education. Be sure to provide information that is not available on your resume. You could talk about your best classes, your favorite coursework, any student councils you were on, awards or accolades, and scholarships earned. \n\nWhile attending post-secondary studies, you likely learned some core skills that would be transferable to your role as a Commercial Broker. Think about what you learned at your highest levels of education and how that knowledge applies to your work.\n\nWhichever direction you choose to go with your response, be sure to tie your answer in with the ways that this educational experience will benefit you as a Commercial Broker.", "\"I have a Bachelors Degree in Management with a major in Marketing. I went to University ABC on a full scholarship and graduated top of my class. My passion for economics, as well as quantitative analysis, really came to life while earning this degree. Since graduating, I have been able to utilize my education in a multitude of ways, not only in terms of my business knowledge but also by utilizing new soft skills such as time-management and project planning.\"", "\"I recently completed my MBA, after taking online coursework in the evenings and weekends for the past two years. I am proud of this accomplishment since I worked in tandem with this coursework, and still graduated top of my class. I am eager to apply my new skills and knowledge to this Commercial Broker role. When it comes to consulting and strategy, I now a complete idea of how to elicit information from others and synthesize that information into a cohesive story. I have a better ability to see the big picture and gained more creative and conceptual ways of thinking.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Tell me how you developed and nurtured your largest existing client.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know how you took a new lead and grew it into your most lucrative account. Often, the most significant client accounts are the ones we nurture the most, so it's essential that you can walk the interviewer through your process of finding a new prospect, gaining their business, and continuing to win new business or referrals from that relationship. Share a success story about how you've done this in the past.", "\"In my current position, I developed my largest existing account by visiting their office regularly to give market reports from their region and the surrounding 3 miles. Showing that I was keen, and prepared to service their company with a great sense of attention and local knowledge, was what they wanted to hear. The company went from renting their commercial spaces to buying their first location in just six months of meeting me. I continue to grow this account by offering important knowledge and always delivering the best commercial real estate opportunities to them first.\"", "\"With my larger accounts, the success has all come down to building relationships through offering market overviews and leasing reports regularly, without being prompted. Excellent customer service skills and personalized touches help, as well. With my largest client account, I am sure to remember their kids' names, birthdays, and congratulate them on company milestones.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "How will you complement Company ABC, if you were hired?", "answers": ["Company ABC has an excellent reputation, faithful clients, and a robust team of talented brokers. Now, they want to know how you will make an impact on their organization if hired. If you landed the position, what would you bring to their company that would be positive and unique? Assure the interviewer that you are the right fit for this position. If you have a 90-day plan in mind, come prepared to share that with the interviewer.", "\"I have already crafted a 30, 60, and 90-day plan to exceed my training expectations and targets. The plan includes doubling up on my cold calls and making more in-person client visits than expected. I want to knock this out of the park right away and become a top broker at Company ABC within five years.\"", "\"If you hire me, I will compliment your organization in a few significant ways. First - I am a fast learner, and I already bring six years' experience in the real estate industry, reducing my training period. Also, I will bring a robust portfolio of clients with me, which will make a financial impact almost immediately.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Company ABC looks for team members with creative energy. Would you consider yourself a creative person?", "answers": ["Real estate requires creative approaches to selling, marketing, and client relationships. Talk to the interviewer about any interest that you have in creative activities and how you have implemented your creative desires as a Commercial Broker. Even if you do not consider yourself to be a 'creative person,' there is a significant chance that you have made creative minded decisions in your career.  Think of a time when you thought outside of the box!", "\"I am creative in the sense that I am great at seeing all sides of a negotiation, allowing me to be creative in my communication and sales approach. I can use creativity to close a deal, and I am a solid writer when it comes to business presentations and marketing materials. With that said, give me a paintbrush, and I will have no idea what to do. I suppose creativity comes in all forms!\"", "\"I am someone who alternates between the right and left sides of the brain, but I will always consider myself a very creative person. I admire the creativity and unconventional thinking required in the real estate business.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Commercial Brokers often need to give formal presentations to prospective and existing clients. Tell me about your experiences giving high-stakes presentations.", "answers": ["The fear of public speaking is the #1 phobia we have, as humans. It comes ahead of the fear of death and the fear of spiders! It is okay to find public speaking a bit intimidating but do assure the interviewer that you are capable of communicating well in front of large groups. \n\nHave you taken any courses or training in public speaking? Perhaps you have so much experience that it comes second nature. Either way, assure the interviewer that you are capable of giving high-stakes presentations without choking. If you have given presentations, you can also mention the topic, what the setting was, and to how many people you presented.", "\"High-stakes presentations to groups of decision-makers is a big part of being a Commercial Broker. I am prepared to successfully roll out important communications to my existing and prospective clients. I have experience preparing pitch decks that are engaging and thorough. I utilize different techniques, such as graphs and charts, to make presentations fun, interesting, and engaging.\"", "\"I do not have a lot of experience in presenting to large groups; however, I have spoken to small groups of clients, perhaps, 4 to 6 people at most. To strengthen my communication and public speaking skills, I joined Toastmasters last year. I am now a confident public speaker and am sure that I could present in front of many people."]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "As a Commercial Broker, how do you stay abreast of the real estate happenings in your community?", "answers": ["It's essential to Company ABC that you keep up to date on what is happening in your community when it comes to real estate. As a Commercial Broker, it's vital that you know what your clients may be facing in the current market conditions. Be specific and talk to the interviewer about the resources that you lean on, to stay abreast on industry happenings.", "\"To stay up to date on what is happening in our city, in terms of commercial real estate, I subscribe to a few industry blogs, as well as a couple in the banking industry. My top resources are (A), (B), and (C). Of course, I also stay on top of market reports released by Company ABC as they are beneficial and robust.\"", "\"I read a variety of commercial real estate publications such as Real Estate Magazine. I also read many articles and reports from Forbes, Deloitte, and NAIOP. If you have other resources that you recommend, I am all ears! I love to research, learn, and grow.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "How do you go about nurturing relationships with business owners, landlords, and developers?", "answers": ["As a Commercial Broker, the relationships that you build can make or break your business. Your role is likely driven by commission, meaning that your healthy relationships are how you earn a paycheck. By developing and nurturing great relationships, you will gain repeat business, be offered valuable referrals, and build a fantastic reputation in your area. Discuss how you go about nurturing these crucial relationships. Try to be as specific as possible.", "\"I certainly appreciate the opportunities that come my way and know that I can only do as well as my network allows. To nurture relationships with business owners, landlords, and developers, I create and publish monthly market reports, sending them out to my email list. I will pop into local businesses to say hello and ask if I can help them in any way. I am a big advocate for small business. The entrepreneurs that I work with know that I give them a lot of word-of-mouth business. When my clients are successful, I am successful too.\"", "\"I have a well-organized call list so any prospect or client from the past will hear from me by phone once every six weeks. I believe that this contact is important since most people rely on email or text messages these days. A more personal approach such as a phone call, or even an in-person pop in can make a significant difference when it comes to building and nurturing relationships.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "How well do you know the community dynamics and demographics in your region? Why is this an essential factor for a Commercial Broker?", "answers": ["A large part of your success as a Commercial Broker will be directly associated with how well you know your market. When you are on top of your market and understand the commercial real estate needs and issues in your region, you can then act more quickly and provide your clients with the knowledge they need to make timely and lucrative decisions. \n\nDiscuss how well you know your community dynamics by talking about how many years you have worked in the area, how you conduct your research or other tactics that you utilize to remain in-the-know. Be sure to address why you believe this knowledge is pertinent to your success as a Commercial Broker.", "\"My knowledge of our city is advanced. I was born and raised here, spending most of my life living and working in the downtown region. This community knowledge has helped me in many ways, including my ability to learn about changes and movement in real estate faster than many other brokers in the area. I have a reliable network of local business owners, landlords, and developers who know my name simply from my exposure and tenure in the community.\"", "\"I believe it's essential for me, as a Commercial Broker, to have a thumb on the beat of my community at all times. Community knowledge is the power I need to make suitable recommendations to my clients. I read market reports from other brokers, demographic reports released by various councils, and continually keep in touch with news stories and events that are impacting all parts of our city, and surrounding area.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Company ABC prefers to see at least two years of residential real estate experience before moving our team members into Commercial Broker roles. Walk me through your experience as a residential real estate agent.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you have earned your place as a Commercial Broker by first cutting your teeth in the industry through the residential real estate route. Most Commercial Brokers will first work for a few years in the residential space, learning about the industry before taking on commercial responsibilities. In some states, prior residential real estate experience is a requirement before you can earn your commercial license. \n\nSince this question is open-ended, be sure to keep a well-organized answer that is brief. The interviewer is not asking for a career autobiography; rather, some important career highlights that will make you stand out from other candidates. For this reason, be sure to include some of your most significant career wins as a residential real estate agent.", "\"Before entering my first Commercial Broker role, I worked as a residential real estate agent for ten years. I won many awards such as Top Agent, Top Producer of the Year, the Million Dollar Club Award, and a President's Club award. I had earned my way to the top, and although I loved the success, I wanted a new challenge. After these achievements, I decided to try my hand in the commercial side of the business and haven't looked back since.\"", "\"I began working residential real estate two years ago and experienced great results shortly into my career, entering my agencies' President's Club after just year one. I have put a strong focus on cold calling as well as more modern marketing efforts, which have paid off significantly. Now, I am ready to add commercial real estate to my portfolio.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Do you hold a CCIM (Certified Commercial Investment Member) designation? If so, when did you obtain this certification? If not, why have you not pursued this step?", "answers": ["A CCIM (Certified Commercial Investment Member) designation tells others that you are a knowledgable professional in the commercial real estate sector. The designation process ensures that Commercial Brokers are knowledgable in a variety of related topics, including financial analysis, market analysis, negotiations, decision analysis, investments, and ethics. \n\nIf you hold a CCIM designation, give some details as to when you obtained this certification, and why it's important to you. If you do not have a CCIM designation, be sure to show that you are open to the idea.", "\"I have been CCIM designated since 2017, and scored 92% on the exam. I have been in good standing with the CCIM for over ten years. I believe this designation to be critical to my brokerage career because of the recognition it gives me in the commercial real estate industry. Also, my membership allows me access to a significant network of other real estate professionals across the country.\"", "\"Although I have not yet gained my CCIM designation, I do have plans to take the exam when I meet the minimum requirements, including working in the commercial real estate industry for at least two years. Being offered this Commercial Broker role with Company ABC is an excellent start.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "What do you know about the CCIM Institute and the role it plays in your Commercial Brokerage career?", "answers": ["The CCIM Institute is one of the most recognized commercial real estate professional organization. They have been around since 1967 and are an excellent resource of learning and education for aspiring and seasoned real estate professionals. The interviewer would like to know how familiar you are with the CCIM Institute, what your involvement has been with the organization. Keep your response positive and give some detail that goes beyond basic stats about the institute.", "\"The CCIM Institute has helped me develop my career as a Commercial Broker, a great deal. I have taken coursework through the CCIM, including 'Financial Analysis for Commercial Investment Real Estate,' 'Evaluating Retail Development Projects,' and Market Analysis for Commercial Investment Real Estate.' I believe the CCIM to be an incredibly important factor in the development of commercial real estate agents, and a valuable upholder of ethics and values for our industry.\"", "\"I recently applied for CCIM membership after moving to this state. I aim to be a recognized leader in the commercial real estate industry and believe that this membership is an essential first step. I understand that the CCIM offers membership to not only Commercial Brokers, but also leasing professionals, asset managers, appraisers, property managers, developers, attorneys, and more. I am eager to become part of the extensive CCIM network.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Coming from a clients' perspective, what are the most significant benefits of hiring a Commercial Broker?", "answers": ["There are many benefits of hiring a Commercial Broker, and the hiring authority at Company ABC wants to make sure that you wholeheartedly believe in the services you will be offering their clients! \n\nSome of the benefits that you could mention include the fact that brokers are incentivized to help their clients since they work on commission! They are experts on the market since it's their full-time job to know what the market is doing in their region. Other benefits include faster turn-around time on property acquisition and the fact that you will only see the best properties that suit your needs. Also, the negotiation skills of a Commercial Broker can save a customer thousands of dollars! \n\nTalk to the interviewer about what you believe to be the most significant benefits of hiring someone like you.", "\"From a clients' perspective, and the most important value-add that I hear most often from my clients, is the fact that hiring a Commercial Broker helps them to cut through the noise, get their project underway, and finalize deals in the fastest way possible. We can take on the research, and perform effective negotiations on a busy business owners' behalf. That gift of time and financial savings is priceless.\"", "\"The benefits of hiring a Commercial Broker include the fact that buyers get professional advice from industry trained people on the best properties to buy, what the real estate marketing is doing at the moment, and what a fair price is to pay for a commercial property. My clients most appreciate the fact that they can continue to focus on their business while their real estate project comes to life.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "What do you know about the services offered by Company ABC?", "answers": ["The hiring authority at Company ABC wants to know that you have performed research on their organization before coming to your interview. Be sure to check out their website, LinkedIn company page, and do a Google search to get a full scope of what they do. Often, online customer reviews can be a helpful resource. Remain positive, showing your excitement to join Company ABC and their menu of professional services.", "\"From the research, I conducted before coming here today, I understand that your top services include real estate development services, leasing, capital markets, and commercial investment management services. I am most skilled in commercial investment management services and look forward to contributing to your esteemed team.\"", "\"I am very familiar with Company ABC and know that your top services include lease space searches, property and portfolio management, and real estate investment opportunities. I am eager to learn more by joining your team and becoming a vocal advocate for the Company ABC brand.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Company ABC uses technology tools for business development and client service purposes. With which tech tools are you most familiar?", "answers": ["Any real estate agent, whether on the commercial or residential side, knows the importance of using a CRM to keep track of clients and sales pipelines. You likely use other tools in the form of apps on your phone and tablet, to help you succeed in your job. \n\nPopular tools used by a Commercial Broker include a CRM like Salesforce, an email integration tool like MailChimp, a document-generation tool such as DocuSign, and lease comparable databases such as CompStak. \n\nDiscuss which tools you are most experienced in by naming them and mentioning your level of expertise. You can rate your skill level as beginner, intermediate, advanced, or expert. Alternately, you can rate your skills on a 1-10 scale.", "\"The tools that I use every day, many from my phone, include DocuSign, MailChimp, CompStak, and Salesforce. I am an advanced user in SalesForce and lean on it for many factors of my sales process, including lead nurturing, creating a cold calling pipeline, and follow-up prompts. These tools have helped me immensely when it comes to building my business as a Commercial Broker.\"", "\"I am most familiar with Salesforce, having taken several levels of their online training, including their Prosell Training. I consider myself an expert level user in Salesforce CRM. As far as other tools, I have some basic familiarity with a couple of email integration programs such as MailChimp and Sendlane. Could you share with me the tools used by your brokers at Company ABC? I would be happy to get a head start on my learning.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "How do you feel about cold calling? Walk me through your cold calling training and experience.", "answers": ["Commercial Brokers lean on a lot of cold calling activities, especially when they are beginning their career. The interviewer wants to know that you will do what it takes to earn new business for Company ABC and your professional portfolio. Discuss your cold calling activities in the past, including how experienced and comfortable you are making cold calls. Second, be sure to mention any training you have received in the art of the cold call.", "\"What I know and love about cold calling I attribute to the Dale Carnegie training that I attended earlier in my career. I took, 'How to Cold Call and Build New Customers,' a course that gave me more than just the basics when it comes to cold calling, pre-sale activities, and building long-term, positive relationships with clients. Today, I conduct around 100 cold calls per week with a stable 10% conversion rate.\"", "\"I had to learn to love cold calling since I was intimidated by the idea, in my earlier career. I did some research and came up with a success formula for cold calling. The steps include first being familiar with the company's unique selling point. Second, identifying the decision maker before my call. Next, learning as much as I can about that person and the company before ever making the call. Once I am comfortable in my knowledge level and research, I ask myself how I can add value to their current situation. My answer to that question is the value proposition that I bring when they pick up the phone. At first, I used a script; however, now, I have the confidence in myself to speak on the fly, leaning on my research and expertise as a Commercial Broker.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "The top Commercial Brokers at Company ABC are highly competitive with themselves. What challenges are you looking for in a position?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you see this position as a challenging next step in your career. Company ABC wants to know that you are never complacent and that you like to set goals for yourself, remaining competitive against your own best performance. Make sure that you are familiar with the company job posting, allowing you to discuss the challenges present in this role.", "\"I am looking for a position where I can better exercise what I learned while earning my CCIM designation. My current position has simpler real estate opportunities, a lot in residential and fewer in commercial, and so I seek to join an organization like Company ABC where I can be part of more complex commercial real estate projects.\"", "\"I have worked as an independent broker for many years and seek the challenge that comes from working for a larger agency like Company ABC with enterprise level clients. Your company has been on my radar for quite some time, and I would be thrilled to join your experienced team of Commercial Broker.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "What is the most important trait a Commercial Broker should possess?", "answers": ["The interviewer at Company ABC knows that you will probably answer this question with traits that you see in yourself! Think of a unique characteristic that you believe all Commercial Brokers should have. Be sure to go beyond the surface and avoid saying things like, 'people-person,' for instance. Dig a bit deeper. Some examples of essential traits may be:\n\n- Curious\n- Achievement driven\n- Strong sense of duty\n- Dominant\n- Ability to handle emotional disappointments", "\"In all of my years in real estate, and primarily as a Commercial Broker, the one common trait that I have seen between myself and my successful colleagues is an air of dominance. I am not talking about a dominance that is off-putting, but a dominance that is authoritative and leads the client to the right decision while managing negotiations in a way that makes all stakeholders feel confident and comfortable.\"", "\"In my opinion, one trait that every Commercial Broker should have is the ability to handle the emotional ups and downs that come their way. In any given day, a sales professional will have a few wins, and then a few losses. It's important to be able to navigate disappointment, without it affecting your mood or future performance.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Would you cold call every day for a year if it meant you had a steady client list afterward?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking to see if you'll put in the long hours of grunt work to reap the rewards of a stable pipeline of business. People often focus on the wins of sales when talking about their career. For instance, they focus on the commission or the closing of a big account, but they will gloss over the hours and years of work it took to get to that point. \n\nIt's vital that you show you know you're not going to 'phone it in' and have your career, customers, and commissions handed to you without a lot of sweat and hard work. With that said, answer honestly. Put your spin on it. Don't say, 'Yes, of course.' Give it some thought and make the answer truthful and accurate to you.", "\"I am more than willing to put in time and sweat equity into building my book of business via cold calling; however, I would hope that my years of experience in client development and closing of large accounts would give me some additional latitude. I am fully prepared to roll up my sleeves and make many cold calls as well.\"", "\"I love being on the phone, connecting with people, and teaching them all the ways that my knowledge as a Commercial Broker can help them. I can't expect success to be handed to me overnight. So, yes, I'd be willing to cold call for a year to catapult my career. An upfront investment in the long-term health of my career is something I can get behind.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Tell me about a time you faced rejection in the real estate industry. How did you handle it?", "answers": ["Real estate sales positions are full of rejection, so the interviewer wants to know that you've faced rejection in the past and have overcome it. Share an example of a denial you've faced and how you overcame it. Choose a case that has a positive outcome and shows that you learned from the situation and bounced back quickly. \n\nIf this is your first real estate position, share a relevant experience from your post-secondary experience, a volunteer role, or your athletics career. Perhaps you didn't get into your first choice university or make the soccer team. Whatever it is, show how you took the rejection in stride, learned, and moved on with gusto. Pivot back to how this life experience has taught you something and try to connect it very clear to your potential new sales role.", "\"I was far along in a sales cycle with a potentially huge customer who had shown a ton of interest. I'd even flown out to see them for what was one of the final sales presentations with all stakeholders. They'd known the pricing and acted as though this was a formality before they bought. Well, then they went dark. I literally could not get anyone on the phone or via email. It was a devastating experience. It would have been a huge commission, a massive amount of recurring revenue for the company, and a landmark account. It took about a week to wrap my head around it and then I doubled down and was determined to find a new, bigger account to land. And, while the sales cycle took more than three months, I finally did it. It's all part of the gig with real estate, and it still stings when that happens, but I know to take it in stride and go find another bigger, better account next time.\"", "\"I initially applied to the College of Business at ABC University and did not get in. It was my dream school and the first step in my life plan, so it was a blow to be rejected. I took a day or two to mourn the loss of that dream and then figured out a plan B that would still get me where I wanted to be. I decided to go to a local college for a year to get some credits done and got a 4.0. I reapplied to ABC Business the following year and got in, with a scholarship. This situation taught me that I might get knocked down, but will always get back up - and usually, there's a lesson to be learned from it. Now I still have a plan B and am ready to be agile whenever a roadblock appears. I think this type of agility and determination has prepared me for a successful career in real estate.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Company ABC often asks our Commercial Brokers to work as part of a team. Tell me about a contribution you made to the last team you worked on.", "answers": ["As a Commercial Broker for Company ABC, you may be asked to participate in client meetings and presentations or work with senior brokers to develop follow-up materials for clients such as lease comparisons and market overviews. Often, you will need to coordinate information with other departments and brokers. It's time to show the interviewer that you are a team player. Talk about a time that you were expected to achieve a goal in a team setting. Discuss the role that you took on, and how you went above and beyond to ensure that your contribution made a difference.", "\"My most notable contribution was my ability to analyze and predict market trends, and then create a successful marketing strategy for a challenging piece of commercial real estate that nobody else wanted to tackle. As a Commercial Broker, significant growth can come from taking on projects that may seem undesirable and completely knocking them out of the park. This initiative showed my team that it's worthwhile to exit your comfort zone.\"", "\"In my pod, I am the only one with education in finance so I have made it my mission to create educational materials for the rest of the pod so they can feel more comfortable when presenting numbers to developers and commercial real estate investors. Having this information helps them feel more confident and natural when they are making their pitches to prospective clients. I was not asked to do this, but I knew it would benefit everyone and the agency as a whole if we portray ourselves most professionally.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "How do you react in the face of failure? For instance, when you lose a client or a significant deal falls through?", "answers": ["Many Commercial Brokers earn money based on commission, which means that losing a client, or a prominent real estate deal, can be extra painful when it happens. The interviewer would like to know how you react when it comes to significant setbacks. Everyone handles stress and disappointment differently, but it's vital that you show the interviewer your ability to pick yourself back up and try again. Point out how your setbacks do not affect others in your office, and that any losses you face fuel you to work harder next time.", "\"I am an internally competitive person by nature, and thus, I look inward when a setback occurs at work. I become internally frustrated when my goal fails, or a perceived 'done deal' falls through. It's important to me that I do not let my emotions around these setbacks impact my coworkers. When situations like this occur, I will go through a mental rundown of what I could have done differently. It can certainly be emotionally taxing, but I also learn a ton from processing these mistakes.\"", "\"Setbacks can be trying, but I have to learn how to lose before I can learn how to win. While I never enjoy a setback, I use them as a stepping off point to something even better.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "At Company ABC you will be interacting with clients of all types and personalities. How would you build a relationship with someone who intimidates you?", "answers": ["Commercial Brokers work alongside other brokers, realtors, developers, business owners, and other decision makers; all with their own approach and personality! When working in the real estate industry, stakes are high, and personalities are big. \n\nWe have all been in a situation where we find a co-worker, a boss, or a client a touch intimidating. Show the interviewer that you have the smarts, and maturity, to recognize when this is happening, and the ability to overcome whatever factor is causing those feelings.", "\"As a Commercial Broker, I often have to give presentations and pitches to groups of decision makers, who can be quite intimidating. I stand tall and remind myself to be proud of my work, no matter what they may say or think. By doing this, I am oozing confidence, and the situation becomes so much easier. Also, I recently read about 'mirror neurons' in the brain. These neurons mean that people respond with similar facial expressions and demeanor so, if you are friendly and approachable, others are more likely to be as well.\"", "\"I have a great method that I learned in sales training, earlier in my career. This method is beneficial when I have to make cold calls or have a challenging conversation with an existing client coming up. The trick is to practice, out loud, with someone else. Have that person throw possible objections out and then try to overcome them. Once I have had this conversation a few times in practice, it becomes much easier in a real-life situation.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "If hired, what can Company ABC do to help you achieve your career goals?", "answers": ["If Company ABC asks you this question, you should be jumping up and down with excitement! As many organizations turn away from the hierarchical organizational structure and lean more toward a flat organizational structure, you will begin to see companies show more concern for the growth and development of their employees. Jackpot! \n\nBe prepared to discuss how you like to be motivated, what you may need in your compensation package or even the type of workplace environment you know you need to be successful. You can also discuss learning opportunities, or continued education options, that are piquing your interest.", "\"I read on the Company ABC website that you offer continuing education opportunities for your brokers who are performing well. This offering is the best way that you could support my career goals. I am a major proponent of continued education opportunities and professional development, and I am pleased to see that Company ABC is as well.\"", "\"Thank you for asking! I am seeking to join an organization with a solid succession plan for each position within their company. When I have a clear understanding of where my role can take me, I can better plan for the future and take more direct and successful steps. Could you share with me what Company ABC has in place for broker development and future growth?\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Commercial Brokers at Company ABC encounter challenging situations every day. Do you consider yourself a patient person in the face of a challenge?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you consider yourself a patient individual, in the face of significant challenges. An attitude of impatience can cause a lot of stress and anxiety in your coworkers and clients, so it is essential that you can showcase your ability to remain patient and professional in workplace situations. \n\nPatience is indeed a virtue but can be challenging to maintain when it seems that situations continue to push your buttons. Show the interviewer that you possess the ability to keep your cool in challenging conditions.", "\"As an experienced Commercial Broker, I certainly understand that challenges will come my way daily. I am patient in the face of a challenge, but I would say this patience is more of a learned skill than something innate. I have worked to become more patient and not demonstrate frustration in the workplace. I know when challenging situations push me, it's counterproductive, so I remind myself of that. I know when I'm running out of patience and am proactive asking for some time to regroup as appropriate.\"", "\"I do consider myself a patient person. I would rate myself an 8/10 for patience because I certainly have room to grow, but I do have a very long fuse. If I need a patience boost in a challenging situation, I will take a step away, and return to the situation when I feel ready. I recently read, 'The Power of Patience' by M.J. Ryan, which gave me some excellent new methods for coping with stress.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Our clients mean everything to us at Company ABC.How do you define exceptional client service?", "answers": ["Company ABC needs to be careful in who they hire, ensuring that their standards of excellence are continually met. Excellent client service goes beyond doing precisely as your expected, and it's more than having a smile on your face when the client is looking. Superior service means that you actively seek out the opportunity to deliver more than the standard broker would. It means thoroughly listening to your clients when they tell you what they need. Also, it means offering support when your client may be in a little bit over their head.", "\"Repeat business and referrals are what I am after when it comes to the satisfaction of my clients. When it is time to close out an account, I openly ask them what I could do better next time. This added step helps me to improve my service. Good customer service starts with the ability to take and implement feedback.\"", "\"I define good customer service by not allowing any 'traffic jams' in the real estate sales cycle, which is a challenge to do! The moment a client feels there is a hiccup, the moment the sales process gets railroaded. Excellent service includes seeing potential pain points before they even happen.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "Give me an example of a time when you had to be extra diligent to meet a deadline.", "answers": ["When working for an esteemed brokerage like Company ABC, it is essential that you deliver their standards of excellence in everything that you do. The interviewer would like to know that you are a diligent individual when it comes to deadlines and respecting the needs of your clients. Are you determined to complete your tasks on time, or do you frequently drop the ball? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to act diligently on the job.", "\"Working in commercial real estate is always about last minute changes and tight deadlines! Recently I worked until 4 AM to deliver an updated proposal for a very particular client. You do what you have to, to make your clients happy. I am not afraid of hard work.\"", "\"Last month, I had a client who made a lot of additional and last minute changes to our project. Despite the changes, our deadline remained the same. Our senior broker was becoming stressed that we would not meet our deadline for the market analysis presentation, so I agreed to stay late three nights that week to ensure that we met all expectations.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Brokerage", "question": "What would your most recent boss say about you if they were asked to describe your character?", "answers": ["Company ABC wants to ensure that you are a fit for their company culture and that you will get along well with their other team members. Think of some words that best describe your work ethic and character. Be sure to include descriptive words that will ensure you are a standout candidate. Most people, when asked this question, will say they are 'reliable' and 'easy to get along with.' A more thoughtful and unique answer to this question will give you a better chance of impressing the interviewer. For instance, you could say that you are: \n\n- Attentive\n- Committed\n- Persistent\n- Motivated\n- Tenacious", "\"I believe my most recent boss would describe me as persistent, goal-oriented, not afraid to push the envelope, and always wanting more. Also, I think he would add that I am always up for a professional challenge.\"", "\"My character is important, and I am proud of the reputation that I have developed over the years. When you call my boss for a reference, I believe she will say that I am tenacious, motivated, and led by numbers and data.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Why are you the best candidate for Company ABC?", "answers": ["It can feel unnatural to brag about yourself, but when the interviewer asks this type of question, there is no better time to highlight what makes you the top choice for Company ABC. Discuss the characteristics and career accomplishments have made you a star in the past. Perhaps you have received some academic awards or have been given individual accolades in your most recent position. There is nobody like you, and now you need to express that to the interviewer!", "\"When I read your job posting I smiled from ear to ear because it was as though you had written it with me in mind. I know that I am the best candidate for this role because I have eight years of exceeding my sales goals, residential and commercial real estate sales experience, and I know the local market inside and out. These factors make me ideally positioned to help Company ABC continue to succeed in this region.\"", "\"Although I am new to my career, I believe my success with Company ABC will come from the soft skills that you are looking for, including great communication and research abilities. I learned a lot about communication and research while obtaining my business degree and look forward to putting these skills to work for you.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "How did you bring value to your most recent position?", "answers": ["Company ABC needs to know that if hired, you will bring your best work and talents to the office every single day! The interviewer wants to hear more about your recent successes and bragging points. \n\nThink of the top skills you apply in your current job and any accolades you have received lately. Perhaps you influenced changes that saved the company money. Maybe you were the top-grossing salesperson last year. Think of your strengths in action! If you are reliable, talk about how consistent your work has been and how you are in constant support of your coworkers. If you have a strong work ethic, share how you accomplished a project amid harsh obstacles.   \n\nIf you are new to your career, you can talk about any value you have brought to a volunteer position, a team sport, or a group project at university.", "\"As a top-grossing lease agent, I bring immense financial value to my current company. I've been among the top three agents since starting in the role. I also helped create a community group within the organization that spearheads volunteer efforts on behalf of our development company. This effort has greatly increased our exposure and reputation in the region as a mixed-use property developer.\"", "\"I care deeply about delivering value to the group projects that I am a part of in my university coursework. I work hard to understand the goals of the group so that I can position my talents to serve the group best. This approach is one I plan to bring to Company ABC as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Tell me about a development project you worked on where a conventional approach was not suitable.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know about a particular development project you have worked on where your creativity was required, and a conventional approach was not the answer. Explain how you have implemented creativity in the workplace, and what the outcome was. Display for the hiring manager how you can think outside of the box when necessary, benefitting Company ABC if hired.", "\"When the economy fell, a lot of developers and business owners were struggling. At that time, a conventional approach was to take out new ads on the radio or TV. Social media was starting to become a major advertising outlet - and it was free. I launched a social media campaign that was very successful. We were able to generate new business by advertising free leases for three months, on two-year contracts. The message spread quickly, and we saved thousands upon thousands of dollars on our advertising budget.\"", "\"I was on a developers' marketing team for my internship; where we had to alter our processes to meet our customer's environmental impact challenge. We had to completely change the way we built their advertising plan, keeping zero waste in mind. It was a fun challenge, and I learned a lot about sustainability in engineering and design.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Tell me about your experience working alongside sales, leasing, and project managers.", "answers": ["The purpose of this question is to uncover your ability to work cross-departmentally or cross-functionally. The property development industry requires all hands on deck to complete a project successfully so, Company ABC needs to be very mindful of hiring only team players. \n\nIf you do not have experience working collaboratively, or if you come from a very independent work environment, that is okay too. Discuss how you are looking forward to working in a team-focused environment and how your personality and characteristics work well in team environments.", "\"In my current role, I work alongside two project managers at all times. I also collaborate with our architects and designers regularly. Everything we do requires a high level of communication and organization. I completely understand the importance of collaborating with all stakeholders in these high-level property development projects.\"", "\"My jobs have all been highly independent; but I have still answered to supervisors across a variety of departments including sales, legal, project managers, and leasing agents. What makes me a great team player is that I communicate often and clearly. I am a good listener who takes direction very well, and I am self-aware, ensuring that I do not overstep in my role. I am here to learn and collaborate.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Competition in the mixed-use development industry is gaining momentum every day. What sets Company ABC apart from our local competitors?", "answers": ["The hiring authority needs to see that you have done your homework when it comes to the competitive landscape of mixed-use development in your region. Take a look at the Company ABC website, look for times they have been in the news or won any awards for exceptional work. Perhaps they stand out by longevity, how much they give back to the community or the number of 5-star reviews present online.", "\"You are the longest-running developer in this region when it comes to downtown projects that promote luxury live/work opportunities. I appreciate the fact that you give so much back to the community, including the hours that your teams invest in charities such as Habitat for Humanity every year. I am excited to join such a seasoned team of thoughtful professionals in the development industry.\"", "\"What sets Company ABC apart are the hundreds of positive reviews I read online from happy customers! Your office, retail, and living spaces are beautiful, and the feedback is consistent; you produce high-quality apartments and townhouses that people can afford while still providing exceptional amenities.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "How do you manage your projects and all the moving parts that come along with new developments?", "answers": ["This question is your opportunity to show off your exceptional organizational and multi-tasking skills! Talk to the hiring authority about the number of projects that you have on the go, and how you keep track of it all. Assure the interviewer that you are well-organized and capable of handling a significant volume of work. If you are new to your career, you can lean on the fact that you had many projects and assignments on the go while attending post-secondary studies.", "\"I manage my projects through the use of a team-based project management system called Trello. Do you use a similar tool here at Company ABC? When given a new project to start, I plug in all the information, files, deadlines, and requirements into Trello so that everything is in one place. From the big picture to the finer details that come with the mixed-use property development industry, myself and my team can easily access it all.\"", "\"While in university, I became a huge fan of prioritization, using the calendar on my smartphone and color-coding tasks according to urgency. I plan to use a similar style of project organization here at Company ABC, to help me stay on top of every important project detail.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "How do you like to be recognized for your accomplishments?", "answers": ["The mixed-use property development industry can be competitive, and generally attracts people who enjoy a challenge and recognition when they do something great. The interviewer would like to know how they can recognize you at Company ABC when the time comes. Perhaps you enjoy financial perks, kind words, added responsibilities, or title promotions. Share with the interviewer how you would like recognition for your hard work.", "\"I am a highly competitive person who is compensation driven. I like to see recognition for my accomplishments through monetary bonus' or contests where the stakes are high. In my current role, I have earned awards such as an iPad, gift certificates, and financial bonus' for sales made. These are all excellent ways to recognize my accomplishments.\"", "\"I feel best when I know how my hard work has positively impacted another person. In the property development industry that can be helping someone find the best office space in the area, where they can enjoy a great live/work/play balance.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "How do you handle communicating bad news to a client, such as a delay in project timelines?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you can adequately handle being the bearer of bad news now and then. One of the toughest parts of communication can be delivering bad news to your clients and other stakeholders. Whether it is discussing a delay in project timelines or other hiccups in the development process such as budgetary issues, delivering bad news doesn't come easy. Assure the interviewer that you can handle this type of task in a transparent, concise, and professional manner.", "\"I sure hope to deliver disappointing news rarely; however, I understand that this happens from time to time. When I do give bad news to a client, I respect the fact that they will want me to give it to them straight. I will be honest and clear in my communication, avoiding any cliches or terms that sugarcoat the situation. It's best my client knows exactly what the issue is so that we can continue a relationship built on trust and honesty.\"", "\"I have found that communicating with respect and the intent to support the client is the best approach. It is important to communicate what parts of the project are off track and what resources are available to get the project back on track.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "I would enjoy some insight into what makes you unique. Tell me something about yourself that is not on your resume.", "answers": ["Although this question may not have much to do with the duties of this job, the purpose of this question is for the interviewer to assess if you are a fit for the team and culture at Company ABC. You are under no obligation to talk about your relationship status or kids. Instead, stick with the fun facts that will make you memorable, and show some personality! At the end of your response, try to tie in how this hobby or interest compliments your career.", "\"I am taking wine training to become a hobbyist sommelier. So far, I have completed my WSET level 2 and am onto my third level shortly. I am specializing in French wines. It's been a fun hobby of mine for a few years now, and I am building a wine collection of my own. I find that many of my clients are wine enthusiasts, so this hobby also helps me to make common ground with the people I come across at work.\"", "\"I am a big fan of learning new languages! So far, I am fluent in English, Spanish, French, and Italian. Next, I am set to learn Mandarin, which will be an incredible challenge. I believe these languages will also be beneficial to me in my career as there will be fewer language barriers with international clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "What are your strengths, as they relate to the property development industry?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about what makes you great at your job. The strengths you mention can be skills or qualities that help you overcome difficult circumstances or accomplish challenging tasks in the property development industry. These skills help you to effectively manage projects, understand client needs, and help you make deals happen! \n\nTry to talk about unique strengths, staying away from the typical answers such as 'organized,' 'good communicator' and 'multitasker.' A hum-drum answer to this question could cost you the job. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about a couple of your unique and stand-out strengths and why those will help you to be successful in this role. Tie these strengths into the qualities mentioned in the Company ABC job posting, for an even stronger response!", "\"I believe my greatest strength lies in my analytical and creative mind. I have worked to cultivate my creativity and apply it to my work in the property development industry. Understanding this business from project management but also creative aspect sets me apart in a unique way, as others tend to either be creative or analytical.\"", "\"My strongest skills that help me daily are my people skills, and the ability to close a sale without being pushy. I relate to the client, get to know them and their needs, build excellent rapport, and can make solid buying and leasing recommendations that suit them. They happily buy and then send valuable referrals.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "How do you feel about saying no to a client with unreasonable requests?", "answers": ["Real estate and property development are very customer-focused industries as they rely heavily on reputation, referrals, and repeat business. The interviewer wants to know where you draw the line when it comes to outlandish requests or needs that you cannot deliver. \n\nGive an example of a time when you had to say no to a client or prospect. Assure the interviewer that you are happy to accommodate any Company ABC client within reason! Complete your answer by solidifying the fact that you put your clients first.", "\"Many of my clients think that I perform miracles overnight, especially when it comes to contract changes and special requests. I once had a client tell me they needed a guarantee that they would double their revenue if they moved their store to one of our new builds. Of course, I could not promise anything like that. What I did do, in exchange, was offered them a month of free rent so that they could put more funds into marketing as they amped up for their move. The client was happy in the end and signed a four-year lease.\"", "\"Clients who demand the impossible are not the ones that I try to attract or keep if I can be frank. I love when clients have special requests and innovative ideas that I can bring to the attention of my head office; however, demanding something unreasonable is a different story. I had a client once demand that I fly to their city for a face to face meeting the next day if I wanted to keep the account. They were a challenging account with minimal spend. My director said no, I could not. So, I let the client know that I was happy with Skype or book them in when I was in their city next. They refused and fired me. They were not an ideal client, and I quickly recovered because I continued to put my best efforts towards my honest and loyal existing client base.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "What do you know about the workplace culture at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The hiring authority wants to know that you have researched Company ABC and their complete offering before your interview. Workplace culture is a critical factor when considering a career move. Assure the interviewer that you have put thought, research, and consideration into how their culture will fit into your needs.", "\"I have researched Company ABC through LinkedIn, Instagram, and on Glassdoor. Your employees have great things to say, and overall, it seems that you have fun while you work. I am looking forward to joining an organization, like yours, that is upbeat and thoughtful with an eye on developing and giving back to the community at the same time.\"", "\"I know that you have a great reputation with your clients and that you treat your staff very well. I have a friend who interned with Company ABC last year, and she said it was one of the best opportunities she could have asked for, coming right out of university.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Tell me about a career related goal that you set and did not reach.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you are ambitious but also able to recover when you do not reach your career goals as expected. Tell the interviewer about a goal you set for yourself, but failed to meet. Show Company ABC your ambitious side and that, rather than giving up, you are going to try to achieve that goal again. Everyone has goals they have failed to reach, so do not be embarrassed to talk about past perceived failures. The interviewer is more interested in knowing that you are persistent and tenacious.", "\"This past year, I wanted to double my sales, earning a commission check of $80,000. I worked very hard by making additional cold calls, doubling up on my client touchpoints, and being available for my clients 24/7. In the end, I did not reach my goal. However, I did beat my quota by 40%, which was still an excellent achievement. I aim to achieve my goal for next year by incorporating more marketing materials and opportunities for property tours.\"", "\"I set a goal to receive a promotion to property manager last year. I did not get the promotion; rather, they transferred an existing manager from an alternate location. It was a disappointment, but I understood their side. It's often easier to transfer than to train a new person. To overcome this obstacle, I am seeking a new role with an organization like Company ABC where there are more growth opportunities present.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "What does the 'live, shop, work, play' lifestyle mean to you?", "answers": ["It's time to show the interviewer that you have an understanding, and an appreciation, for what mixed-use properties bring to the table. You understand that many people, perhaps yourself included, appreciate the fact that they can live in an area surrounded by buzz, locally-owned businesses, people who can walk and bike to work, and then enjoy the outdoor spaces when the work is done. Give a genuine and heartfelt response to what the 'live, shop, work, play' lifestyle means to you.", "\"I have seen many communities in our city shift to the 'live, shop, work, play' lifestyle and I greatly appreciate what these developments do to boost the areas where they are built. The freedom that these developments offer for business owners and dwellers alike is terrific. The concept helps with environmental sustainability as studies show that mixed-use developments encourage more walking and biking as opposed to driving. Flexible spaces are economical and land efficient as well. I believe that with mixed-use developments, everyone wins.\"", "\"I recently moved into a Company ABC development, and I wouldn't change it for the world! I get to walk out of my lobby and grab breakfast at a family-owned bakery and coffee shop. I can zip down the bike path to nearly any activity I choose. The 'live, shop, work, play' lifestyle is one that I appreciate not only because of what I can do so close to home but also for what the development has done to revitalize the community and boost previously struggling businesses.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "This role requires you to understand property management, operations, marketing, and leasing. Walk me through your knowledge and experience in each of these areas.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to ensure that you have a good understanding of the many facets of Company ABC. In the property development industry, you will likely have exposure to business activities surrounding the management, operations, marketing, and leasing of mixed-use properties. \n\nIf you have experience in these areas, take the time to walk the interviewer through your career, expressing your level of expertise through a 1-10 scale or ranking your level of understanding from beginner to intermediate, advanced, or expert. \n\nIf you do not have experience in these topics, be sure to remind the interviewer that you are newer to your career, but you are keen on research and learning new skills.", "\"I have worked in real estate for twelve years; three of those years specifically in commercial leasing and the other nine in residential sales. My career path offers a great balance of the skills you seek at Company ABC. I have an advanced understanding of property management, operations, marketing, and sales and leasing. I am eager to take on a variety of tasks here, should I be your ideal candidate.\"", "\"My understanding of property development topics is limited; however, I have been doing some studying on sales and leasing, and marketing for mixed-use properties since I applied to this role. Should Company ABC hire me, you will find that I am a fast learner and a great researcher. I will always find the answers needed to perform my job to the best of my ability.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Do you have experience creating or managing a marketing plan for establishing new customer relationships?", "answers": ["If you are applying to a sales or marketing role with Company ABC, chances are you have some experience with marketing plans for building new customer interest in the property development space. Discuss the knowledge you bring in generating new leads, and the part you have played in sales and marketing plans. \n\nIf you do not have experience in creating a marketing plan or working within one, be sure to mention that you are here to learn and grow. Enthusiasm will be the key to a successful response for you.", "\"I have around seven years of experience in sales and marketing with a focus on new client development. For most of my career, I have been in business development, creating plans for customer attraction and prospecting. I am excellent in managing marketing plans, which includes analyzing the ROI of the approaches that I put into motion.\"", "\"I am a recent marketing graduate, so the bulk of my experience is from projects that I put together while obtaining my degree, and the case studies that I immersed myself in, during that time. I am very open to learning new tips and tricks to establishing new customer relationships, increasing revenue, and how a solid marketing plan plays a role in achieving those goals.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Business owners and home buyers often expect service on weekends and evenings. Are you available to work outside of a typical 9-5 schedule?", "answers": ["In the real estate development industry, work hours often occur outside of 'the norm,' and the interviewer wants to see that you can deliver what they need from you despite an irregular schedule. \n\nTalk about times when you have worked outside of the usual 9-5. Be sure to mention any restrictions that you may have, while positioning them as a positive rather than a negative.", "\"I understand that the property development industry often works out of the typical 9-5 schedule. I am happy to be available when needed; either by my leadership, my clients, contractors, or vendors and suppliers. In my current position, I do have the freedom to come and go to ensure my kids are picked up from school and brought home. With that said, I keep my work cell on 24/7 and am always just a phone call away.\"", "\"Being new to my career, I am more than happy to work any hours required of me; whether that be weekends, evenings, or holidays. I completely understand that clients often work during the day so they may need to make calls or site visits outside of typical hours.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Talk to me about the project volume you are accustomed to handling.", "answers": ["It's a good idea to go into your interview with a sense of the volume of projects that you would be handling; should you be the successful candidate. The Company ABC website should give you some idea of the number of projects they complete every year. If the answer is not there, it's okay to ask! \n\nTake note of your busiest times in past jobs, and come prepared to discuss the type of work volume that you have managed in the past.", "\"I read on your website that you develop around five new mixed-use projects per year, which is a very significant volume. Company ABC has developed some of my favorite buildings in a variety of neighborhoods across the city, and I look forward to contributing to those projects. I currently manage one development project at a time, which averages around 40 residential units and six for-lease commercial spaces. I am confident that I can take hold of the project volume here with full competency.\"", "\"As a recent graduate who is also completing my final internship, I am accustomed to a large volume of work. Currently, I handle important paperwork and communication for a 70-unit residential building as the intern and assistant to the senior leasing agent. In addition to this, I carry a full-time course load and am earning exceptional grades. Could you tell me more about the project volume that you handle and the workload for this specific role?\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Name for me some benefits of mixed use developments.", "answers": ["Company ABC puts a significant focus on the value that their developments offer to their clients and the community. It's vital that you go into your interview with a solid idea of why mixed-use property developments are essential for the community and your clients. Some reasons include: \n\n- They offer a greater variety of single and family housing options when it comes to design and lifestyle. \n- They provide more development options in areas that are dense, such as city centers.\n- They reduce pollution and traffic by encouraging live/work/play lifestyles. \n\nBe prepared to give the interviewer your ideas on the benefits of mixed-use developments.", "\"There are layers and layers of benefits to mixed-use developments. When it comes to people who work and live in the area, dwellers do not need to commute as often. This factor saves on costs and helps the environment. Next, mixed-use developments are commonly used to revitalize older or underdeveloped areas. These improvements then fuel local economic growth as people become customers for local business owners. Lately, the tax revenue that comes from increased property values is significant.\"", "\"I have researched a great deal on mixed-use developments and how they impact communities and the economy. I believe the greatest benefit is how fresh developments can revive forgotten communities. When this revitalization occurs, small business owners, grocers, retailers, and restauranteurs all benefit from more business and new customers.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "How do you remain on top of changing market conditions when it comes to the sale and lease of commercial and residential property?", "answers": ["The hiring authority wants to know where you get your information from, and which resources you turn to when you want to be in-the-know on industry trends and happenings. Your market will change regularly, and part of your role working for a mixed-use property developer is to know how these market changes will impact your clients, employer, and prospects. If you are new to the industry, it's okay to ask for resource recommendations!", "\"I subscribe to a few industry podcasts for overall global news related to property development and real estate. I read the local newspaper daily for clues on what is happening in various communities around me. Also, I rely on my network and industry events to stay in-the-know on new developments and legislation in my area.\"", "\"I am very open to suggestions on how to stay in tune with what's happening in the property development industry in our region. At the moment, I read online magazines such as Urban Developer and Land Developer Global.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Do you have experience leading teams of contractors or tradespeople? If so, how many, and under what job descriptions?", "answers": ["The answer to this question should be straightforward for you. List for the interviewer how many people you have led, what their job titles were, and a bit about yourself as a leader. If you do not have leadership experience, lean on an example of a time when you led others without leadership being a formal requirement of the job.", "\"I have led teams of up to 25 people; including general contractors, plumbers, electricians, carpenters, and junior project managers. I take pride in being a communicative leader who expresses deadlines and clear expectations from the start. My strength is in gaining buy-in from the team as a whole, ensuring a harmonious work environment with a focus on safety.\"", "\"I am new to my career, so my leadership responsibilities have not been formal; however, I do tend to take on a leadership style role in a group setting. Even while attending university, I had a keen ability to keep teams working well together on major group-based projects. I look forward to gaining even more leadership experience with Company ABC and, one day, leading a team of my own here.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Walk me through your education, and how it will help you in this role with Company ABC.", "answers": ["An education in construction, property management, or real estate may not be a requirement at Company ABC but related education is always a bonus. Your training may be in the form of a formal degree, online coursework, workshops, or certifications. If your educational background is not related to the industry, take some time to think about the ways that your training will translate to this particular position.", "\"I have a Bachelor of Science in Construction Project Management from XYZ University. My courses focused on communication and presentation skills, technical mathematics, materials and methods of construction, and project cost estimation. I was top of my class in most of the technical coursework and found that to be my specialty. This education has helped me to carve out a very successful career in the mixed-use property development space.\"", "\"My formal education is in Business Analysis. Although not specific to construction, property development, or real estate; my knowledge is still highly transferable. Valuable coursework comes in the form of math, research, and engineering topics. If you require specific construction-related coursework, I am happy to add this to my career plan.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "If hired at Company ABC, how will you source new sales and leasing opportunities?", "answers": ["Ideally, developers will have their units pre-sold, or leasing agreements in place while projects are still in development. It's essential that no space remains empty by the time a mixed-use property is fully developed. \n\n Company ABC wants to know if you have a sales or marketing plan in mind for the times when there is space available in a development; whether that be residential or commercial space. \n\nGo to your interview prepared with some ideas on how you will make an impact shortly after being hired. In the development and real estate realm, there are plenty of ways for you to drum up new clients and opportunities. Discuss how you will be a success story, from the start!", "\"If Company ABC hires me, I will source new sales opportunities by first warm calling the leads that have gone dry in the past three months. From there, I will ask for referrals from happy clients of the past. Some other marketing strategies of mine include strategic social media posts to garner interest from your target customer demographic.\"", "\"I am well versed in online and social media marketing, so I plan to begin a social media account focused on the design and beauty that Company ABC delivers with each development. I will also comb through the company CRM to uncover potential prospects and leads that have gone cold in the past few weeks.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "How do you approach networking and reaching out to local realtors?", "answers": ["This question is hyper-targeted to your specific approach in networking. Show the interviewer that you have a keen interest in growing your local network, which will only increase your success with Company ABC. \n\nIf you do not have experience in networking, because you are new to your career, you can answer this question hypothetically. Be sure to display an understanding of the fact that networking is key to success in the property development industry.", "\"My preferred approach for networking and reaching out to local realtors includes cold calling and attending industry events. I am an outgoing person and find that I make the most meaningful connections when I am on the phone or face to face with someone, versus sending them a stale email! I am an active part of the sales network in our area, and look forward to bringing my connections with me when I join the Company ABC team.\"", "\"I did some networking when looking for an internship in the property development sector. I joined ABC Builders Group and met some wonderful people who were willing to help me get a great start in my career. If hired at Company ABC I will continue to attend industry events. If you have recommendations for me, that would be great. I am eager to jump on new opportunities to network.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Do you have experience giving property tours?", "answers": ["As a professional in the mixed-use property development, you understand that property tours are essential because they allow agents to gain knowledge on the currently available inventory for commercial or home properties. Property tours show off what your company is completing, and is a way to entice new buyers, and business owners to invest in your development. Discuss any experience you have facilitating tours. If you are new to your career, be sure to express your willingness to learn and be trained in how to lead a tour properly.", "\"I have given many property tours in my career and enjoy doing them as well. Conducting property tours allows immersion in conversations that I may not have had otherwise. I can get to know people, gauge their interest, and build rapport with interested parties.\"", "\"I understand the importance of property tours, and that they can happen at a few stages of development. I have been learning more about virtual tours as well, in hopes of staying up to date on the latest trends in the industry. I look forward to learning more at Company ABC and eventually conducting tours of my own.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Do you have a solid understanding of architectural documents and tools such as blueprints and models?", "answers": ["As a mixed-use property developer, Company ABC will have employee expectations that include the ability to read basic blueprints or understand simple models. Of course, you don't need to be an architect! But you should have a basic ability to hold your own in client or internal meetings, through property tours, or with pre-sale activities. \n\nDiscuss with the interviewer your exposure to architectural documents and models. If you are new to your career, express your willingness to learn more before beginning your role with Company ABC.", "\"I have had exposure to blueprints and models for many years, having sold condo developments in the past. I am very confident in my ability to understand the architectural documents shown to me in this position and, if there is a factor that I do not know, I will quickly learn what I need. The topics I am best versed in include blueprint symbols and abbreviations, interpreting 2D views of 3D objects, and using the information found in these models and drawings to create an overall picture of a development project.\"", "\"I recently enrolled in a course at my local college called 'Blueprint Reading Basics.' In this four week course, I will learn about the types of drawings used during the design process, print reading, standardized blueprint symbols, and abbreviations for residential and commercial buildings.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "When have you worked with someone opposite of your personality or work style? How did you make the partnership work?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to understand if you are a team player and someone who can work with a variety of personalities. Everyone's work style is unique, and it's crucial that this doesn't stop you from being a great collaborator! \n\nDiscuss a project you were working on and the ways your work styles differed from your teammate. Maybe they were disorganized when you are tidy and in control. Perhaps they fretted over the small details when you're a big-picture thinker. \n\nWhatever the situation, explain how you came together to conquer the project. Show the interviewer that you are capable of giving merit to different working styles, even if they do not match your own.", "\"I approach work by scheduling meetings in advance and having a list of items to review at the start of each day. My peer was rarely prepared for meetings, spent a great deal of time talking about personal items, and operated in reaction mode to many situations. I took it upon myself to speak to that person about our different styles and come to an agreement on how we could work best together. I am open to working with all types of people and welcome challenges with a smile!\"", "\"My current boss approaches work very differently than I. She is great with closing deals but is a tornado in meetings where I am highly organized but not as sales driven. One day over lunch, we talked about our working styles, and what drives us. This conversation led us to brainstorm ways that our styles could complement each other in the workplace. We worked together much more cohesively after that conversation.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Are you applying for a job with any Company ABC competitors?", "answers": ["The world of property developers can be a small one, so the interviewer would like to know if they will need to compete with other companies, let alone their local competitors when it comes to hiring you. \n\nTell the interviewer about your search so far without disclosing every single detail. Answer this question with a balance between creating some urgency in the interviewer, and not divulging every aspect of your job search. Be sure to solidify your interest in Company ABC as well.", "\"It's safe to say that it's a candidate's market right now, with so many available opportunities in the commercial and mixed-use property development industry. With that said, I am only applying to the best roles with companies with which I can grow. I look forward to further discussing your opportunity here at Company ABC.\"", "\"I am in the process of exploring opportunities with property developers that appeal to me; however, I am selective on where my applications go. I am very excited about this particular opportunity with Company ABC because of your solid reputation and amazing mixed-use developments that are transforming our city. I look forward to the next round of interviews.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "Compensation aside, what perks do you want to see from Company ABC?", "answers": ["Company ABC wants to know what type of financial or workplace perks would motivate you to accept a job offer. Be prepared to offer the interviewer some direction on what is important to you. Aspects that you could mention include: \n\n- Health and dental benefits\n- Work-life balance\n- Workplace culture\n- Opportunities for growth\n- Continued education opportunities\n- Property discounts!", "\"In this role, I will be in and out with clients, performing property tours, and conducting market assessments so, for me, the room for creativity and a flexible workspace is significant. This flex could include an open office where it's easy to collaborate or the ability to work from home when needed.\"", "\"I am a recent university graduate so, what is most valuable to me, even above total compensation, are education and learning opportunities. I want to grow in the property development industry, and further education would be beneficial.\""]}, {"topic": "Mixed+Use+Property+Development", "question": "What attracts you the most to this position with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know what you will enjoy most in this particular position with Company ABC. A great 'fit' should go two ways, so the interviewer wants to be sure that they will offer you what you need, and that everyone's expectations are well-aligned. \n\nTo best assess this, you can look at a few factors: \n\n- Do the day to day activities stimulate you? \n- Does the position push your skill level and offer a challenge? \n- Does the job require you to do enough of the tasks that you love most? \n- Is the company well established; offering you job security?\n- Do you like the person to whom you would be reporting? \n- Are there opportunities present for career growth and advancement? \n- Do you like the overall vibe of the location and office? \n- Will you be able to stand behind their product confidently?", "\"What attracts me most to this particular position is the job security offered at Company ABC. Despite severe economic downturns, your company has maintained strength and integrity. I am confident that I would have an opportunity for exponential growth, should I be your chosen candidate.\"", "\"This position is interesting to me because it would grow the skills that I started to develop while obtaining my business degree. The past few years, I have been developing my knowledge of real estate, property development, economics, and infrastructure. This role seems to be a happy blend of all these topics.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "What is your first reaction when you do something wrong at work or make a mistake on a project?", "answers": ["This question is an honesty based query that will show the interviewer a lot about your character. How you react to an error made will tell the interviewer a great deal about you and your honesty level. If you made a mistake that could land you in a lot of trouble, would you try to hide the incident, or would you tell someone on your team right away, and have the situation rectified?", "\"I am my own biggest critic, so when I do something wrong or make a mistake, I am the first to voice it and look for a fix. I am independent and smart, so I am confident in my ability to repair any errors I create. If necessary, I would bring a colleague or manager into the situation to help me repair the situation. Most importantly, I am honest and also open about my work; owning up to any mistakes that I make.\"", "\"I fully believe in honesty and immediately repairing what I have done wrong. I am not too proud to admit when I have made a mistake, but it's for the good of the team that everyone is open and honest when an error happens. Taking these situations as opportunities to become better is very important.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "Tell me about a time when you were particularly skilled in prioritizing tasks and completing a project on schedule.", "answers": ["Company ABC has many projects on the go at one time, and they want to hear that you have a plan in place to keep yourself organized and well-prioritized. The interviewer wants to evaluate your time management skills and diligence when faced with prioritization. Start by mentioning that you are typically an organized person. From here, dive into a recent project where you were particularly skilled in staying organized and on deadline.", "\"I am a naturally organized individual. Without proper organization, a project can get out of hand quite quickly. I was recently involved with a project that required 30 hours of my time in two weeks while I was also in the middle of several other projects. I was able to stay on track with visual reminders, mid-day check-ins, and a strong support team. I ended up working some overtime, but that is par for the course as a software engineer.\"", "\"When working as a freelancer, every project success was entirely my responsibility. Every new client project that I took on meant a great deal of organization on my part. To minimize time lost, I like to map out my plan of attack and then start the action sequence. I use a few tools like Monday and Evernote, to help me remain organized.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "What type of work environment do you need to be the most productive?", "answers": ["Company ABC wants to know how they can maintain a healthy level of productivity from you, should you be hired. Maybe you can be productive in any environment or, there are particular types of situations that you find distracting and would prefer to avoid. Either way, discuss your preferences with the interviewer. Be sure to research the kind of environment that offered in this position before the interview.", "\"I understand that your work environment is very collaborative and flexible. I currently work in a similar environment and find that I can be very productive when there is the 'buzz' of a team around me. I can also be productive in quieter environments, although that isn't my preference.\"", "\"I am productive in work environments where there is little nepotism or hierarchy. As I grow in my career, I aim to be the type of manager who has an open-door policy where my teammates can feel comfortable coming to me with questions and needs. This type of environment is one that I appreciate in return. I understand that Company ABC hires from within whenever possible, and encourages employee growth and promotion.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "How is Company ABC transforming the future of real estate?", "answers": ["The way you answer this question will show the interviewer how much research you have done on Company ABC before your interview. Take a look at any awards and accolades Company ABC has received recently. Perhaps there are articles and press releases that you can rely on as well. Mention how you believe they are disrupting the real estate industry, and be sure to show your excitement for joining their team!", "\"I believe that Company ABC is transforming the future of real estate by creating a one-stop shop for all things real estate. Typically, buying or selling a home is a stressful event; one has to hire a broker, a mortgage lender, a lawyer, and more. With a company like yours, you help home buyers through each stage in a well-timed, incredibly well-supported platform. What you are doing is entirely shaking up the industry, and I cannot wait to become a part of it.\"", "\"Not only is Company ABC transforming real estate by giving buyers and sellers more options than just a typical real estate exchange with a realtor, but you are empowering a significant movement in a very traditional industry. Real estate has been the same for decades, and now, thanks to Company ABC the cumbersome process of buying and selling a home is changed forever.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "Describe an ongoing problem at your current job, that you were able to overcome.", "answers": ["Every place of employment will have its challenges, so the interviewer isn't asking for you to talk about the things you didn't like about your job. Remaining positive, speak to the interviewer about a specific issue that you were able to overcome in your previous role, based on your unique skill set. The way that you answer this question will also show the interviewer the type of responsibilities you currently hold.", "\"In my current position, one ongoing problem is the disconnect and separation in the workplace between the developers, designers, and the sales team. I have begun to overcome this by implementing weekly lunch and learns where everyone is welcome. The topics are focused on a variety of situations that we all face in the company. I feel that the better we all understand each other's jobs and functions, the better we can all get along. So far, this approach has been working very well.\"", "\"An ongoing issue in our department was a lack of funds allocated to the projects that our leadership had already approved. It seemed as though they wanted us to perform miracles with very little financial bandwidth. To overcome this, we banded as a team to decide where we could cut from our individual budgets to ensure the delivery of a solid product.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "What do you know about the workplace culture at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer needs to see that you have researched their offering, ensuring that Company ABC is an excellent fit for your next career adventure! Mention some points that you know are offered in this role, discussing which areas are most exciting for you.", "\"I know that Company ABC was one of the first to market with so many online property and real estate services. Being so innovative, it's no surprise that your workplace culture is collaborative, fun, and focused on bringing out the creativity of your teams. I hear that you host game nights, hackathons, happy hours, and a robust health and wellness program. There are many more dimensions to our workplace culture that I am eager to learn more about.\"", "\"You had me at your speaker series offerings! The fact that Company ABC offers lunch and learn sessions with industry leaders and savvy professionals on business, leadership, and trends in the online industry, tells me everything I need to know. Your organization focuses on building up your staff and helping everyone grow into bigger and better roles.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "Pick an app on your phone and sell it to me.", "answers": ["This question is a catch-all for any interviewer in the online platform industry because it covers a candidate's knowledge whether they are in sales, design, engineering, or other development based role. Think of your favorite app on your phone, and discuss with the interviewer why it's your choice - convincing them that they should download the app as well! Feel free to have some fun with this question.", "\"My absolute favorite app is the Rosetta Stone app. It has nearly al 5-star ratings and is widely known as one of the most effective ways to learn a new language. The interface is easy to navigate, and you can also learn from the desktop experience. I learned to speak Spanish in just three months. Imagine what you could do with a new language?\"", "\"Snapchat is by far the app that everyone should download. Snapchat users are introduced to lenses and augmented reality, which is an exciting concept that is not new, but new to everyday users. Snapchat is amazing for real-time effects and videos, and you are introduced to fun tools like face detection. Did you know that it would take someone ten years to view all of the photos ever exchanged on Snapchat? One hundred eighty-seven million daily users can't be wrong!\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "In your opinion, what has been the most exciting advancement in the real estate industry this year?", "answers": ["The hiring authority would like to see that you are up to date on what is happening in the real estate industry and that you come from a position of understanding as far as how Company ABC is disrupting an industry dripping in tradition. Discuss the resources you use to stay on top of industry trends and be prepared to discuss one exciting advancement that you find memorable.", "\"I recently read an article on blockchain technology and how it's impacting the real estate industry. In a nutshell, because of something called tokenization, landlords may be able to use blockchain to sell portions of ownership in their properties. The article also touched on how property titles could be more securely and more conveniently stored, thanks to blockchain ledgers. This topic is one that I am sure impacts the approach at Company ABC for future offerings on your platform.\"", "\"I have been learning more about virtual reality, and it's fascinating how VR is impacting the real estate industry.  Viewing a property is one of the most critical steps to renting or selling a property so, the implementation of VR for walkthroughs is a game changer. VR allows prospective tenants and homebuyers to walk through properties in off-hours and without an appointment. I look forward to seeing how Company ABC will leverage VR on your platform this year.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "We primarily lean on React, Redux, Node.js, Java, Python, and SQL. With which language are you most familiar?", "answers": ["The interviewer is giving you some insight into the languages that you will be using at Company ABC should you be the successful candidate. Considering the list of languages, think about which ones you have the most experience with, and where you are most comfortable. If you'd like, you can rank your skills from beginner to intermediate, advanced, and expert. Doing so will give the interviewer a good idea of where you stand with each language.", "\"I am familiar with all of these languages; however, my skill level varies between these. I am most experienced and comfortable with Python and SQL, having been immersed in these for the past ten years. With React and Redux, I am a beginner level user and very open to working on strengthening these skills.\"", "\"In my current role, I work nearly all day in Java and Node. I would consider myself an advanced user in each of these. When it comes to Python, SQL, React, and Redux, I am an intermediate user. I can certainly commit to learning these further, before my first day at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "Who are Company ABC top competitors? Name for me one factor that we do better than the rest.", "answers": ["The work that Company ABC is bringing to the world is relatively new in the online real estate industry. For that reason, it's essential that you come to your interview with a great idea of what they do, and who is trying to compete with these efforts. Take some notes on their competitors and take the time to compare services. What do you believe is the stand-out factor for Company ABC?", "\"I understand that you were one of the first to market with a full-service online property platform and today your top competitors are (A), and (B). One factor that stands out to me, above all the rest, is the fact that your platform offers many add-on services such as a sales proceeds calculator, home estimation tools, and local news feeds for your users to stay in-the-know on what is happening in their marketplace.\"", "\"Research shows me that your top competitors are (A), (B), and (C), although Company ABC was the first to market with many services that went beyond offering static listings. I understand that you source insights from the people who live in particular neighborhoods so that you can offer new buyers a deeper understanding of the community they are interested in moving. Passing along advice from local real estate agents, brokers and other real estate professionals is another reason why Company ABC stands out above the rest.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "Company ABC is seeking a degree in Computer Science or another technical discipline. Walk me through your education.", "answers": ["The interviewer will likely have an idea of your education background from your resume. What they are asking is for you to take a few minutes to bring the experience to life for them! This question offers you the opportunity to discuss your major, any special academic recognition, or even what your favorite coursework included. Discuss the strengths gained during your post-secondary training and how those skills will be used in your new position with Company ABC.", "\"I have a BS in Computer Science, I also have a great deal of on the job training and certifications, all listed on my resume. One of the biggest take-away's from my post-secondary experience was learning how to manage my time while working on multiple projects successfully. I perfected my multi-tasking skills and am eager to bringing those to work for Company ABC, in addition to my extensive technical knowledge.\"", "\"I completed my Bachelor of Engineering Technology from Penn State University in 2004. During that time, I specialized in Data Management and Analysis. I graduated with a 3.99 GPA, as one of the top students in my class.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "If you had to choose just one, what would you consider to be your technical specialty?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know about your particular areas of interest or ability, and what makes you a unique candidate. Talk to the interviewer about your strengths and be sure to highlight any specific skills that you excel in. It's a great idea to highlight particular skills listed inside the Company ABC job description.", "\"Technically speaking, my one greatest strength is in my front-end expertise. I love making pragmatic architecture recommendations and providing sound decisions that guide the development process.\"", "\"I have been focusing my career on becoming a senior data engineer and would say that data pipeline architecture is my primary technical specialty.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "What types of industries have your previous projects focused on?", "answers": ["The hiring authority would like a fuller idea of the types of projects and industries you have experience within, giving them a better idea of what you will bring to Company ABC; should they hire you. Take a few minutes to walk the interviewer through your work experience; being sure to express how your experience over other industries will help you to succeed in this role.", "\"The bulk of my career has been within the banking and finance industry. This experience will help me with online property listing and real estate services because I understand a lot of the industry jargon surrounding mortgages and lending. Also, I am well versed in the confidentiality, and security needs that come with building a platform that deals with sensitive transactions and large purchases.\"", "\"My previous projects have focused on the healthcare and medical industry. I believe there are a lot of transferable skills between healthcare and real estate. These include the sensitivity of the information stored, the high-stakes present in both industries, and the complexity behind the data. I am eager to learn everything that I can about Company ABC and your platform.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "Company ABC hosts regular hackathons to encourage innovation and autonomy. When have you created a new product, service, or process with the help of your tea?", "answers": ["It's vital that you learn about the various ways Company ABC helps and encourages growth in its teams. A common approach to sparking workplace innovation in the online platform world is 'hackathons.' Typically a hackathon is a multi-day event in which computer programmers, graphic designers, interface designers, project managers, and others involved in software development get together and collaborate on new and exciting software projects. \n\nDiscuss a time when you have acted with innovation and created a new product or even improved an existing service. Assure the interviewer that you are creative-minded and ready to help Company ABC achieve new industry breakthroughs.", "\"I worked on a significant release with my current company last year for which I am very proud. Using real-time data, we launched a program that used public records to estimate a vehicle's value. People shopping for a new car could tap into this database to see what a fair price would be, to pay. Our program used neural networks and computer vision to distinguish between high and low-end finishes, and then we used the real-time data to help empower our users. I can see how an approach like this one would be beneficial within the real estate industry as well.\"", "\"In my previous role, I was fortunate enough to be part of a group that introduced my company to the idea of tiered monthly subscriptions where, in addition to our general customer service, we added premium service options. Our customer base responded very positively, and we kept the program running for a few years.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "This role with Company ABC is highly technical. What is your understanding of this position and the responsibilities that come with it?", "answers": ["It's time for you to assure the interviewer that you bring a full understanding of the technical requirements to succeed in this job. It is essential that you research the role and thoroughly consume the information provided in the Company ABC job description. Keep your answer to the point being sure to use the same language used in the job description.", "\"From our past conversation, understanding the job description, and researching the role online I feel that the job is best described as a project leader working with data and product teams to develop new tools and systems to support the growth of the business. The technical requirements that you would like to see are Python, Java, and AWS services. I am well versed in the tasks and programs you are asking for and am confident that I meet the strict requirements to perform in this role successfully.\"", "\"My understanding is that you seek a candidate with expert level skills in React, Redux, Node.js, Java, Python, and SQL who can train junior employees. I am an expert user in all six of these areas. Do you have any questions about my technical expertise?\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "The online property listing services industry is highly competitive. How will you help Company ABC stay ahead of its competitors?", "answers": ["It is critical that you research Company ABC, and their most vigorous competitors, before your interview. What does Company ABC do best, and who is trying to do it better? Speak openly with the interviewer about your ability to work competitively and how you plan to contribute to their continued success.", "\"I believe the best way to stay ahead of your competitors is to pay a big amount of attention to the fine details. When you put out a great service, others will try to mimic your work, but they will cut corners because they will feel rushed to get it out on the marketplace first. I will contribute to the success of Company ABC by committing my most attentive work to you every day.\"", "\"I think that the best way to stay ahead of competitors is to keep your offering as simple as possible while remaining innovative. People want simple, easy-to-use services, which they can understand and access easily. What I've seen from competitors lately is that they overcomplicate their products.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "Market research is at the heart of what we do at Company ABC. How do you approach a project before beginning?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about your work habits and how you prefer to approach a new project. If you have a sense of how Company ABC prefers to approach their work, you should discuss that method. For instance, if the interviewer tells you that they prefer extensive research before beginning a project, that is your queue to talk about your excellent research skills.", "\"I agree that market research is the backbone of any project, especially in the online property listing services industry where data is constantly changing. Without research, important details are missed, and much time is wasted. I like to research before starting a project so that I can lay out a plan and understand the potential hurdles as well.\"", "\"Although there may be some instances at Company ABC where jumping right it may be required, I always prefer to research before I being a project. I will grab a team member for added support, and ask them to cross-reference my research and poke holes in my project theory wherever possible. Rest assured; I would always follow your preferred methods, should I be hired.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "Company ABC encourages cross-departmental collaboration. Do you have experience collaborating between developers, designers, and other stakeholders?", "answers": ["Whether your work experience is with a startup, a small company, or an enterprise organization, you likely have experience collaborating with people who have different job functions from you. Your ability to work with cross-functional teams will be a significant asset to Company ABC since they are known for leading highly collaborative projects.\n\nIn the past, you may have been asked to work on a project with teams from another department. Share any challenges that came up and what you learned from the experience.", "\"Yes, I have indeed worked in many cross-functional environments. Currently, I lead the front-end development team and collaborate with a couple of engineering and design reams regularly. We all work well together to ensure an amazing product that our users love.\"", "\"When I worked for a development agency, I collaborated across departments all the time. The majority of my interactions were with developers and designers. We would meet every week to discuss larger projects and then collaborate through the week as needed. It was a great set-up and ensured smooth progress at all project stages.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "Company ABC operates in an ever-shifting industry. What is the most significant shift you have had to deal with in your career?", "answers": ["Being able to pivot and adapt is a critical skill to have at Company ABC and when working in the online database industry. The interviewer would like to know the types of challenges you face in your career and a specific time when you had to adapt to stay on track. You need to show Company ABC that you can remain productive in the face of change and that you are resilient. Assure the interviewer that you can adapt to significant changes in a professional manner.", "\"One of the things that I love most about this industry is the fact that I am continually learning and growing; being kept on my toes. The biggest change in my career was learning to report to an entirely new management team when my company merged with a large competitor. It's difficult to adjust, but I was able to keep an open mind, and met some great new people while being allowed to develop my skill set further.\"", "\"I first began my development career when Python was making a serious impact in the programming language industry. I had been trained solely in Java and needed to adapt quickly. I watched YouTube videos for hours every day and took formal online courses. This example shows that I can adapt to the introduction of new programs, software, and languages. I am confident in my ability to keep the pace in this ever-shifting industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "Company ABC has high expectations when it comes to our platform and customer experience. How do you react when you are dissatisfied with the quality, or the outcome of your work?", "answers": ["Because of the high standards at Company ABC, the interviewer would like to know how you respond when you feel that your work does not meet expectations. There will always be a time when you are not happy with the work that you deliver, but your reaction is what will determine whether or not you recover from the disappointment. Show that you have the maturity to be able to respond to dissatisfaction productively.", "\"The last time I was dissatisfied with my work, I asked my boss if there was time for me to re-do the components with which I was not happy. The deadline was tight, but I did not believe the timeline should affect the quality of what I delivered. She agreed and gave me the time to revisit the aspects that I felt were not up to my usual standard. I worked around 5 hours of overtime to get the project exactly where I had pictured it, and everyone was satisfied in the end.\"", "\"In programming and design, there is some room to experiment with our work and bounce back from mistakes. I allow myself to make mistakes, tweak my work, and play around with different designs, for instance. My philosophy is that a creative mind is always seeking improvements.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "Where do you see your career with Company ABC 12 months from now?", "answers": ["Interviewing, hiring, and onboarding is an expensive and time-consuming endeavor for Company ABC. The interviewer wants to know that, if engaged, you will see this as a longer-term fit. Discuss your career plans, goals, and how those fit with what Company ABC can offer you shortly down the road. Describe your passion for this opportunity, and where you see your career taking you! If you are unsure, take a look at the current openings listed on the Company ABC career site and read some of the descriptions for roles a step or two above your own.", "\"I am thrilled to be interviewing at Company ABC for your front-end developer opportunity. I believe with the talents and skill set I bring to your team, we will solve some stimulating challenges. This role is an opportunity I have been seeking for some time now, so I plan to stay for the long term should I be lucky enough to be hired. If I were to have an opportunity for growth at Company ABC, I saw a job posting for a senior front end software development engineer that caught my eye. This role is one I would be happy to grow into over time.\"", "\"One year from now, I would like to see myself climbing the ranks within your engineering team. It's important to me that I continue to learn and grow, applying my skills to the best of my ability for my employer. I saw a Data Engineer position on your website that caught my eye. I would need to strengthen my experience in Python development; however, this is a nice goal to set.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "If offered this role at Company ABC, how will you build relationships with your new coworkers and supervisors?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how you plan to start relationships with your new co-workers and management, should you be the successful candidate. Company ABC works hard to nurture a cohesive workplace culture and environment, so it's vital that you will find your place within the team very quickly. Due to a wide variety of personalities, coworker connections can take time to form. How do you ensure that you have an active line of communication with your co-workers and supervisors, right from the start? \n\nSome ways to quickly build relationships include: \n\n- Be willing to accept feedback and help \n- Offer to join a committee or volunteer assistance in some way \n- Do not have an air of entitlement or act as though you know the ins and outs immediately\n- Avoid all company gossip, at all cost\n- Be early on your first day (and every day after that!) \n- Be well versed in the company's goals, and culture", "\"I like to ask my new colleagues for their best tip, and also what they are currently working on. Developer types like to bounce ideas off of others, which makes these two questions a very effective way to get to know my co-workers and management team.\"", "\"First impressions are everything, and I make a strong attempt to build relationships with all of my co-workers and management team, right up front. I ask discovery questions to learn how I can best support them when working together.  It is also important to gain insight into their preferred methods of communications.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "In your current position, what tasks have you been asked to do that were out of your wheelhouse? How did you succeed?", "answers": ["At Company ABC you may be learning a new industry, and with that comes being asked to perform tasks with which you may not be the most comfortable. The interviewer wants to know how you approach a job when you do not possess the knowledge or experience. Most of us ask others for help or research to find the answer. Highlight to the interviewer that you are competent when it comes to learning and gaining new skills. Show that you do not get frustrated; instead, you take it as an opportunity to grow.", "\"I had minimal training going into my latest role because the company was a start-up with little direction but a lot of pressure on the gas pedal. I received training on their software system but nothing formal surrounding their web stack. Through many online tutorials and YouTube videos, I taught myself how what I needed to do, to be successful at my job.\"", "\"In my current role, I was asked to lead software audit reviews, which I had never done before. I had to learn the standards and how to run an audit appropriately. I was also promoted to a team lead and had a direct report to monitor. This role was my first supervisory position, so I had never approved time sheets or handled employment-related concerns. I asked for advice when possible, and researched on my own time whenever necessary.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "Company ABC is innovating the real estate industry. What does the word 'innovation' mean to you?", "answers": ["The term 'innovation' is often overused in business and development these days and has now become a buzzword that many people don't fully understand. The interviewer would like to know what you feel innovation indeed is. Include an example of a time when you have witnessed an innovative change in the workplace, or when you have exercised creativity. Be sure to express an understanding of the way Company ABC is innovating the real estate industry.", "\"To me, innovation means presenting a new idea or making an existing idea better. It's essential to be innovative in the workplace, but often it's a misunderstood concept. An example of when I was innovative was when our company was facing budget cuts. I suggested that we begin to operate as though the cuts were already made, in an attempt to preemptively save funds. The concept worked well, and we were able to eliminate many unnecessary expenditures. I understand that Company ABC is highly innovative because you are entirely disrupting the way that people approach real estate transactions. I am eager to join your team of talented developers.\"", "\"Innovation means introducing a new process, orcreating a breakthrough. A time when I have been innovative was when I built a new tracking system in our company's CRM. I wanted to create a more accurate way to track projects with a simple option for our sales team to update the project stage. The owner of the company loved my creation, and now it's implemented company-wide.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "What challenges are you looking for in your next position?", "answers": ["Company ABC knows that a perfect employment fit needs to go both ways. Just like the interviewer needs to know that they like you, they want to see that you love them back! Mention a few of the challenges that you are looking for in your next position and be sure to tie them into the duties and responsibilities mentioned in the job posting, or job description. \n\nA challenge you may be looking for could be:\n\n- Learning a new software program\n- Leading a bigger team than you currently do\n- Working on more robust products or services\n- Stepping into your first leadership role\n- Becoming immersed in a new industry", "\"When I started looking for a new developer job, I determined that it was important to find a role with a company that embraces the latest and greatest in systems and software. My current organization is very 'old-school' in their systems, and I do not want to fall behind in my technical abilities. I appreciate that you work with the latest software and are often the first to market with many solutions.\"", "\"For the past six years, I have worked for a wonderful startup with great clients; however, I now have bigger fish to fry! I want to take on a role like this one where I can disrupt a very traditional real estate industry. To be more specific, I also want to learn more about cloud-based data solutions like EMR, Redshift, and Kinesis. I know that Company ABC will be able to offer this challenge and I look forward to growing my career with you.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "Company ABC promotes from within, whenever possible. What do you see as the most challenging task in being a manager?", "answers": ["Being in a management role is always a significant challenge, and Company ABC wants to know that you'll be able to step up to the task when the time comes. Share with the interviewer what you feel is the most challenging part of being a manager, and why. Also, discuss what you could do, or are currently doing, to make this task less complicated.", "\"I believe the biggest challenge in a management role for Company ABC would be to lead everyone effectively when many team members work remote. I like to make a connection with everyone, so I would send friendly check-in emails, for instance, to ensure that  everyone feels like an important member of the team.\"", "\"I foresee the most difficult task as a manager with Company ABC to be the even delegation of work. You will always have team members who are absolute rock-stars, then some who are a bit less enthusiastic or are lower producers. I would remind myself to distribute the work and responsibilities evenly despite my natural inclination to give more work to the high performers. In my current role, I am working with my underperforming team members to prepare them for a larger workload.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "After you implement a solution to a problem, how do you test the effectiveness of that solution?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you have strong follow-through skills and the ability to use data and analytics to support your decisions. The only way to test the effectiveness of a new solution is to keep a close eye on the immediate, and often longer-term, results! \n\nDepending on the situation, you can use data, run reports, and compare/contrast your findings. If you have records of the data before your problem-solving solution, you can track the results of your new solution and analyze in a month, or beyond. \n\nIt can take time to see the results, so having a method for measuring them is essential. Give an example of a time you implemented a solution and found a way to measure the results to check its efficacy.", "\"I like to collect data, as well as anecdotal assessments of new procedures. It's great to have data to confirm if a new procedure was or was not effective, but I am a firm believer, too, in getting the team on board. Plus, as you implement a solution, sometimes those doing the actual day-to-day work or the actual implementation have a more accurate understanding of what's going on or what could be improved. Therefore, I am sure to ask my team how they think it's going, and if it's impactful.\"", "\"In my current role, once our team comes up with a new strategy for a project or product add-on, we will conduct two focus groups. One test group will be on the original plan and the second, on the plan that we want to implement. The use of focus groups is the best way for us to measure if our new strategy will be effective enough to justify the time and funds that will go into the final project.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "Why should Company ABC hire you?", "answers": ["The interviewer at Company ABC wants to hear about that one unique skill that sets you apart from the other candidates applying for this job. Think of your answer as your 'elevator pitch' or your qualifying statement. If you can't think of ways that you are unique, ask a few friends or family members what they feel sets you apart from other people. Their observations may help you understand how you are perceived.\n\nPerhaps you already know what sets you apart! This skill could include any industry accolades, exceptional achievements, additional industry related training, a second language, or how involved you are in the community. Don't be afraid to brag about yourself a bit. In an interview, you are your most influential advocate.", "\"I have over a dozen years of experience in the real estate industry as a developer, giving me a unique edge and insight into the potential of Company ABC products and services. I have creative solutions on how to position Company ABC against the competition, and ideas that will help elevate your platform to the next level.\"", "\"You should hire me because I am unlike anyone else you have interviewed before. When I started at my current company, I was the youngest developer they had ever hired. That didn't stop me from becoming the #1 front-end developer in the company within six months, in terms of production. I am dedicated to my craft and engaged in this industry to the point where I commit myself to take at least one technical or leadership related workshop every business quarter. I am a competitive achiever. You won't be disappointed when you hire me.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "If you had half of a million dollars to build your own business, what would you do?", "answers": ["This question is more of a personal inquiry, allowing the interviewer to gain some insight into what brings you passion. If money was no object, what kind of business would you start? The interviewer will be able to learn something new and unique about you through this question. Avoid answers that would include building a business that competes with what Company ABC is achieving!", "\"If I were given money to start my own business, I would build and sell curriculum for kids who want to learn to code. That would be an interest of mine as well as an additional income stream while still working full time as a developer for Company ABC!\"", "\"That's a great question! If I had 500,000 dollars, I would invest the money into an up and coming tech startup. I have always had a huge interest in technology and advancements, so this would be right up my alley.\""]}, {"topic": "Online+Property+Listing+Services", "question": "If you had to give a TED Talk tomorrow, what topic would you choose?", "answers": ["TED Talks are known for their slogan 'ideas worth spreading.' The platform introduces people to thought-leaders in education, business, science, tech, and other creative industries.  Company ABC has values that include caring for others, prioritizing work that positively impacts communities, and applying original thinking. What topic could you choose, that would add to these values while reinforcing your own beliefs?", "\"If I could give a TED Talk today, I would talk about the importance of embracing and learning lessons from your flaws. Nobody is perfect yet - in our society today, we all try to appear to be so. I would speak about the importance of accepting feedback, asking for help, and continually growing yourself as a person and as a professional.\"", "\"I love TED Talks and have thought about this before! If I could present on any topic, I would discuss how joy and optimism affect our overall attitude and the outcome of our work and personal life. I am a big believer in the law of attraction, so this type of topic would be a primary interest.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "Do you have a Real Estate License or Broker's License?", "answers": ["Some licensing courses are available online, through a real estate company, or at a local post-secondary institute. The licensing requirements will vary from State to State. Talk to the interviewer about any valid licenses you currently hold.", "\"I have a valid State Real Estate license, obtained in 2015. If there are any additional licenses required to work with Company ABC I am happy to discuss those with you.\"", "\"I am currently in final stages of obtaining my Brokers' Licence for this State. I am certified in (name of the previous state you resided in). I will be fully certified and ready to go by the end of this month, which is very exciting for me!\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "How do you handle a Real Estate client with unrealistic expectations?", "answers": ["Some clients will want to check off every box on their wish list, and that property may not exist. Talk to the interviewer about how you ensure that these clients do not leave disappointed.", "\"When I have a client with unrealistic expectations, I will be transparent and immediately tell them that their needs may not be met. I will show them comparable listings on the market and give them ideas on how they can add to the property after purchase to tailor the home to their needs.\"", "\"I do not like to lead clients on as it wastes their time and energy. I am truthful and honest upfront but will also recommend remedies to their unattainable expectations. Compromise is often the key and, for the most part, clients appreciate my transparency.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "As a Real Estate Agent you are expected to be available to your clients on evenings, weekends, and holidays. Are you comfortable with these expectations?", "answers": ["The life of a Real Estate Agent isn't a typical 9-5, Monday to Friday gig. Your clients' primary availability may be outside of 'regular' working hours which means that you need to be available for them during those times. Assure the interviewer that you have a full understanding of these hours requirements.", "\"I am very comfortable with the hours required of me to succeed in Real Estate. If I do need some time off, or a weekend away, I will plan far ahead. My cell is always on me, and my clients understand that they can book showings with me outside of typical work hours, no problem at all.\"", "\"I fully understand the time commitment associated with a career in Real Estate. I'm prepared to make the sacrifices necessary to have a solid career here at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "How would you prefer to be compensated?", "answers": ["Are you looking for a compensation structure based primarily on salary, commission, or a blend of both? Discuss with the hiring manager your preferred compensation.", "\"I am currently compensated primarily on commission with the opportunity to earn a quarterly bonus based on the company's profits. I would like to be compensated similarly in my next position.\"", "\"I am currently making a salary with a bonus incentive on a quarterly and annual basis.  I would like to continue down that path but am open to exploring other compensation components such as commission, etc.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "Why are you the best Real Estate Agent for Company ABC?", "answers": ["What sets you apart from the other Real Estate professionals applying to work with Company ABC? Discuss with the interviewer how you are the best choice for them. Use stand-out facts including top sales numbers or unique skills that you possess.", "\"I feel that I am the best choice for Company ABC because I possess the values that your company encourages. I have been the top Real Estate Agent in my region for the past three years, and bring many great clients with me. My honest approach is a valuable asset to any office.\"", "\"There are a few reasons why you should hire me for this opening at Company ABC. Most important is the fact that my reputation is solid in this market. Also, I bring a great reach into the commercial market in which I understand you wish to gain a stronger footing. Lastly, I am an incredibly tenacious person who will bring desirable listings, in large amounts, to this firm.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "In your opinion, what are the 3 top characteristics that a successful Real Estate Agent should have?", "answers": ["Before your interview, research the internal values and character requirements listed on the company's job description. Tie the needs of Company ABC into your answer when discussing the top characteristics a Real Estate Agent should have.", "\"I feel that to be successful as a Real Estate Agent with Company ABC, one should be attentive to detail, honest at all times, and driven to succeed.\"", "Here are some other characteristics that a Real Estate Agent should have: \n\n- Willingness to remain 'in-the-know' on new trends in the market\n- Ability to grow and maintain a robust network\n- Strong attention to detail\n- Likability and a great personality \n- Drive and tenacity to keep going when the market is slow or a deal is dragging\n- Honest and full of integrity, at all times\n- Self-motivated\n- Avid problem solver"]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "In Real Estate, timing is everything. How do you determine priorities when you have multiple projects due?", "answers": ["When you feel torn between multiple projects or tasks, how do you decide which one needs your attention the most? Assure the interviewer that you can be diligent when it comes to assessing your priorities.", "\"I will determine which project requires my attention by the number of hours we are behind and then the project size. I am comfortable delegating tasks when needed, but I am also aware that these times will require an additional commitment of hours from me. Never have I under delivered on a deadline.\"", "\"I determine priorities based on project value and receptiveness of my client. The most engaged clients generally get my attention and the fastest turnaround.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "Tell me about your most challenging sale as a Real Estate Agent. What sales methods did you use to close the deal?", "answers": ["Some sales are going to be more challenging than others. Talk to the interviewer about the types of closing techniques you use when a stronger close is required.", "\"My most challenging sale was a duplex for sale by a developer when our economy was lagging. It was a high-end property at a time when few people had a healthy budget. I ended up creating a simple but individual website for the property. The website itself created a personality and overall feel for the project. This site created a draw, helped me to gain a strong email list and, from there, I sent out strong branded marketing materials with every touch-point. The duplex sold within 30 days and I was thrilled with the results.\"", "\"Last year I was asked to take on a large multi-family project that had an incredible amount of features; however, the location was not ideal for most working professionals. I took the 'small town feel' approach and created a stunning downloadable whitepaper about the development, which my website visitors could instantly download and share. The whitepaper showed renderings of the family-focused lifestyle that would be present in the new neighborhood and created a feeling that these working professionals knew they needed at the end of the day. The project sold out in record time. I will undoubtedly use this sales approach again!\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "What are your most successful advertising methods when promoting a property?", "answers": ["There are a plethora of advertising methods available in the Real Estate industry. Before your interview, be sure to take note of the advertising methods used by Company ABC. Talk to the interviewer about how your favorite advertising methods match with theirs. If you have unique approaches that have worked well for you in the past, talk about those results as well.", "\"I have utilized many of the same advertising methods used by Company ABC; including print advertising, commercials, and bench ads. These have been great methods for me, but I have come to utilize social media marketing efforts more this year. It's quick, it's cost-effective, and it's on trend which means that I am starting to attract a younger client base.\"", "\"For me, the most successful advertising methods involve utilizing my strong email list. I have over 6,000 active subscribers to my newsletter. This weekly e-newsletter will cover any new properties that I have, and then features one special property. The key is that my e-newsletter also includes tips and tricks for home buyers. It isn't 'salesy' in nature which I believe attributes to its success.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "As a Real Estate Agent you work on 100% commission. Are you confident in your sales skills?", "answers": ["A successful Real Estate professional must be confident in their sales skills since most roles are 100% commission based. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of earning a great living based solely on your sales abilities.", "\"I have been successful in Real Estate for many years, working on a highly commissioned basis. Of course, my first few years were difficult, but I managed to press through those challenging years. I am a solid salesperson and well sought out because of my positive reputation in the industry. This success amounts to many referrals for me as well.\"", "\"Yes, I am confident in my sales skills and my ability to earn a good living on a 100% commission basis. This position will not be my first commission driven role, which also adds to my confidence. In my last position, I was able to earn in the low six figures on the same pay structure.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "Tell me about your post-secondary education and how it has helped you in the Real Estate industry.", "answers": ["Although a post-secondary education is not always a requirement to work in Real Estate, it can indeed be an asset. If you have obtained a degree, diploma, or another form of post-secondary education discuss this briefly with the interviewer.", "\"I have a Bachelors Degree in Marketing which has helped me immensely when it comes to promoting my Real Estate business. Because of this education, I have a strong understanding of multiple marketing and advertising techniques including social media and online marketing.\"", "\"Although I do not have a formal post-secondary degree, I recently completed all studies for my Real Estate license through my local real estate brokerage. I have also completed the state required 90 hours of coursework and am currently working to join NAR (National Association of Realtors). All of this hard work is going to amount to a very successful future for myself, and I am excited to join Company ABC as one of my first big steps in my real estate career.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "How do you ensure that you are meeting your clients' needs when it comes to their property wish list?", "answers": ["Listening to your client's needs is a significant component when it comes to your success in Real Estate. Discuss with the interviewer how you ensure a full understanding of your clients' needs before you begin showing them new properties or helping them to sell a property.", "\"When I start working with a new client I will sit down with them and discuss what they lack in their current property, what they would change if they could, and why. I want to know their motivating factors for change and will start there. Of course, transparency on budget and expectations is vital as well. Open communication throughout the process is my number one priority as a Real Estate Agent.\"", "\"I find that the easiest way to start is by asking my clients what they do not want. From there, we can compile a list of must-have's. I will ask my clients which areas they are willing to compromise and which they are not. This way, I can make a final list of properties and truly only show them the ones that meet those 'must-have' requirements.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "Do you feel comfortable in your ability to properly assess the value of a variety of properties?", "answers": ["Correctly assessing the value of a property is a vital skill as a Real Estate Agent. Discuss with the interviewer your level of knowledge when it comes to property assessment.", "\"I have a few years' experiences in commercial and private property assessment. I am well versed in valuing a wide variety of properties.\"", "\"Yes, I do feel comfortable in this area. I have taken courses related to property management which have provided me with a great deal of knowledge related to property valuations. These courses included topics such as Asset and Facility Management, Residential Property Valuation, Commercial Property Valuation, and Conveyancing.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "How do you handle a client whose expectations are higher than their allowed budget?", "answers": ["Sometimes you will come across clients who have property expectations far above their budget. How do you tactfully handle a client who hasn't received approval for the budget they were expecting.", "\"I cannot control the financial situation of my clients, but I can be creative when it comes to helping them work with what they do have. I bring no judgment when it comes to budget and is happy to work with clients of all types.\"", "\"I understand that some clients have higher expectations than what their budget will allow. I start by showing them properties within their budget that meet the majority of their must-have's. If the property of their dreams does not exist in their price range, they will generally see the disconnect quickly. I have a lot of great contractors and designers in my network that I can utilize in situations where the desired upgrades may be cosmetic and inexpensive. Often, simply helping the client to visualize the fit once small tweaks are made, can make all the difference.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "As a Real Estate Agent, one should have strong negotiation skills. Tell me about your negotiation abilities and how they have helped you in your career.", "answers": ["Negotiation skills are incredibly important in a sales based career. There are many styles of negotiation. Talk to the interviewer about how you close a deal and negotiate the best price for your clients.", "\"When I am negotiating a deal, I abide by the rule 'The first person to speak, loses.' I listen and let the other party talk. Usually, they will say too much, and then I can gain leverage in the negotiation process. This method has helped me to close many deals and hit the top realtor spot within my office for the past three years.\"", "\"Just last year I took an executive negotiation workshop. Ultimately, it changed how I look at deals and negotiations by creating a keen situational awareness within me. It is incredible how much this new found knowledge turned my year around. I am so excited to continue utilizing these tools in my position with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "Real Estate contracts are detailed and tedious. How do you ensure that your contracts are understood by your clients?", "answers": ["Very few people genuinely enjoy reading a written contract, word for word. Being able to explain a written agreement to a layperson in an easy-to-understand way is a great skill to possess. Assure the interviewer that you can help your clients make sense of the paperwork involved in a sale.", "\"Before I give my clients paperwork to sign, I will explain each section of the document in a simple to understand language. I ensure that they have a full understanding of taking particular scenarios and relating them to their specific situation. Understanding all of this empowers my client and empowered buyers always return.\"", "\"Yes, the contracts that we deal with can be incredibly detailed and difficult to understand. Each step of the way I will verbally ask my client if they understand. I also recommend that they use a lawyer if they feel they need additional clarity before signing.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "Tell me about your strongest sales year. What do you think you did differently that year to generate those results?", "answers": ["Before you interview, you have to be prepared with accurate sales numbers. Discuss these sales results with the interviewer and use these numbers to display to Company ABC that you are a great fit.", "\"My strongest sales year was 2016 with 2014 being a close second. In 2016 I closed a total of $$ in sales and $$ in 2014. These results are directly connected to my social media advertising efforts. I increased my advertising budget that year by 20% and saw a 40% return on investment.\"", "\"This past year has been my strongest. It sounds funny, but I created a YouTube channel where I give tips and tricks for new home buyers. So far I have a few thousand subscribers and have had one video go viral. It's been incredible to see the difference that utilizing social networks has made on my business.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "The most successful Real Estate agents are highly motivated. What motivates you?", "answers": ["Typically, employees find motivation in environments where they feel supported and encouraged. The interviewer wants to know how they could motivate you - even on the toughest of days! Be open with the interviewer about the ways you can stay motivated on the job, even when the going gets tough.", "\"It does not take a lot to keep me motivated. If I work in a positive environment with a forward-thinking team, I am a very happy employee. If you see me going above and beyond, a quick thanks or a little token of recognition of my hard work is good enough for me.\"", "\"I consider myself a self-motivated individual who is constantly striving to be better and do better.  I draw inspiration from leaders in the industry and those around me to keep my motivation high.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "What part of your Real Estate career brings you the most stress?", "answers": ["Stress can often be a regular part of the day to day work experience. Talk to the interviewer about which areas of your career are the most stressful. Ensure that your answer does not include a factor that would make you appear unfit for the position. (IE: a bus driver should not find driving to be the most stressful part of the job).", "\"The part of my career that brings me the most stress is when the schedule is running behind due to lack of hustle on my teams part. I like to be on time with my schedule to ensure that my clients receive the help they need.\"", "\"I probably bring myself the most stress because of my drive and desire to be/do the best I can be.  I manage this by focusing my energy on productive activities that are good for my career.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "What makes you a great problem solver?", "answers": ["Employers want to know that you have a methodical approach to problem-solving. Consider the skills and qualities that help you successfully face problems. Perhaps you have a keen eye for detail. Maybe you can see opportunity when others can only focus on the issue. Share your strengths as a problem solver, and your ability to come up with innovative solutions.", "\"I am a great problem solver because I do not allow stress to cloud my judgement and mute my creativity. I am a keen observer with a great memory which allows me to recall unique solutions or ideas.\"", "\"I believe I am a great problem solver because I am sure to gather as many facts as possible, I look at the problem and its potential solutions from multiple angles, and I am not afraid to make a creative decision, that might seem off the beaten path.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "If you had $50,000 to build your own business, what would you do?", "answers": ["If money was no object, what kind of business would you start? The interviewer will be able to learn something new and unique about you through this question. Avoid answers that would include building a business that competes with the hiring company.", "\"If I had $50,000 to build my own business I would open up a community center in my neighborhood that offered inexpensive childcare, cooking classes, and other life skills programs. I am passionate about volunteering and see a strong need in those particular areas.\"", "\"I would choose to invest the $50,000 into an existing business in an industry in which my spouse has an interest. I love what I do for a career, but she has always wanted to be an entrepreneur.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "Have you ever broken a confidentiality agreement?", "answers": ["Companies will have confidentiality agreements for a variety of reasons. These could be to protect their trade secrets or to ensure that you do not bring clients over on the occasion that you leave their company. Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on confidentiality agreements.", "\"I never have, to my knowledge, broken a confidentiality agreement. Despite my reasons for leaving a position, I would never choose to hurt a previous employer in any way.\"", "\"Confidentiality agreements are necessary and important to protect an organization.  I understand the need for confidentiality and take those factors very seriously. I have never broken the trust of my employer.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "On a scale from 1 to 10, how honest are you?", "answers": ["Do you feel that you are a sincere person or do you have room for growth? This question could be a tricky one as nobody is always 100% honest. Answer to the best of your ability and back your reply by speaking about your ethics.", "\"I would love to give myself a 10/10 for honesty but truthfully - nobody is 100% honest all of the time. I will give myself an nine because I always do my best to be as honest as possible.\"", "\"I put a heavy focus on honesty and trustworthiness in the workplace, as well as in my personal life.  Because I strive for complete honesty, I will rate myself as a 10/10. My values are solid.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "How do you define success?", "answers": ["What does success mean to you? Tell the interviewer how you see success and be sure to tie your answer into the success that you plan to bring to this particular position, should you be offered the role.", "\"I define success by my ability to reach the goals that are set out for me. On a personal level, the things I wish to achieve in my life. On a work level, the targets that are set out for me as well as the professional development that I seek.\"", "\"I define success by what we achieve as a team. The project, as a whole, needs to deliver on expectations before I consider the job a success.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "Outside of work, what type of creative activities do you like to pursue?", "answers": ["A genuinely creative minded person will have outside activities aside from what's happening in the workplace. Tell the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you express your creativity.", "\"Outside of work I like to attend dance classes and I also attend the odd paint and sip wine nights at a local wine shop. I also enjoy reading as a way of nurturing my creative side.\"", "\"I am a very physically active person, with a passion for outdoor sports. I love to ski, snowboard, and skate. I play in an adult hockey beer league, as well. How about yourself?\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "What work situations excite and motivate you?", "answers": ["It is essential, for your success, that the hiring manager knows how to keep you motivated and excited to come to work every day. Share with the interviewer what they could do to ensure that you are happy and productive.", "\"I am most motivated, on the job, when tasks are organized, and the vibe is positive. I value strong teamwork and good leadership.\"", "\"I am excited and motivated by winning. I am competitive, and enjoy healthy competition.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "Tell me about your relationship with your previous boss.", "answers": ["Remain positive, even if the experience wasn't. Avoid talking about any previous drama and do not speak poorly of your employer. Keep your answer short and respectful. \n\nIf you had a good relationship with your previous boss: \"I had a very healthy relationship with my previous employer. She was easy to approach, and we would bounce ideas off of each other quite often. I would sum it up as a relationship lead by strong mutual respect.\"", "\"I had a very healthy relationship with my previous employer. She was easy to approach, and we would bounce ideas off of each other quite often. I would sum it up as a relationship lead by strong mutual respect.\"", "If you did not have a good relationship with your previous boss: \"I have had healthier relationships in the past with previous employers, but we did the best that we could. Our communication styles were very different which made it challenging at times.\""]}, {"topic": "Real+Estate", "question": "What questions do you have for me?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the company website and other online resources to ensure the questions you are asking are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers to from merely watching a video on their company site! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the biggest change in this industry over the past 3 years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Thank you for asking - I do have a few questions. What is top of mind when it comes to filling this role? Also, what types of career growth opportunities would follow this position? And lastly, do you have internal candidates who are also interviewing for this position?\""]}]